<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>Blag</title>
	<subtitle>Blog of xypnox, a collection of Literature, Computing and Philosophy</subtitle>
	<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2021-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Notes</title>
		<published>2021-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/notes/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/notes/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The series includes:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;notes&#x2F;intro&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coming soon...&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Notes: Intro</title>
		<published>2021-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/notes/intro/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/notes/intro/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;cover-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;cover-intro.png&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;desc&quot;&gt;
    An introduction to a Journey in note taking.
  &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once when I was foolish and clever, I thought I would never need to write anything down. That I will remember everything forever. I lived with this assumption till I came to my senses.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;moving-notes-to-github&#x2F;&quot;&gt;started making notes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; 2 years ago. I decided on &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.markdownguide.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;markdown(md)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; files in a git repository to be sufficient tooling required. I organized the files in folders and relied on git for version control a.k.a history. The few tweaks, a typora theme, scripts to automate git commands, etc, were enough at that time. I used Typora to edit the notes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with note taking, I also started journaling, rarely. Then at the start of this year,2021, I started journaling properly. Even though I made a lot of notes, I didn&#x27;t use them. I never opened them, let alone read them. Due to the dwindling usage, I started writing all of my notes, about programming and philosophy, in the daily journal itself. This made the organization worse. I didn&#x27;t believe it could be improved because I didn&#x27;t know it could be improved.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then one day, I received a mail from Kevin, the creator of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.dendron.so&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Dendron&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to asking me to try it out. It was one of those mass requests, mailed to starrers of a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;pmarsceill.github.io&#x2F;just-the-docs&#x2F;&quot;&gt;jekyll theme repo&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, as Dendron used the theme for publishing. &lt;em&gt;I did check Dendron out&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. I loved the concept: notes in a hierarchy, in a code editor (&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;code.visualstudio.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;VScode&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;). You got autocomplete to link and lookup to browse and create new notes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From exposure to dendron, I realized that my system had deficiencies, even if it promoted focused note taking and long form writing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typora was a decent note taking tool. I adored it&#x27;s excellent WYSIWYG md editor. It was theme-able. The cherry on top was the editing view: centered cursor with only the current paragraph highlighted, it made writing for long durations a pleasure. However, Typora couldn&#x27;t manage files. You could only open multiple files as tabs on Mac, and the directory structure was clunky. Linking was a distant dream and refactoring a nightmare. A mess of 600 files. &lt;em&gt;..screaming..&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;notes&#x2F;intro&#x2F;typora-notes.png&quot; alt=&quot;Typora&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to switch tools. I knew that several had been made in the two years I had spent with Typora, so the hunt began. Initially, a hybrid-preview editor was my priority. However, after realizing that vscode could act as a very good md editor, I switched to Dendron. The import was seamless. I was ready to go.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started making notes slowly. The lookup and linking made the editor a text browser. The flexible hierarchy made it easy to group and organize notes. Moreover refactoring was very powerful, it updated all the links as well. Embedding and a live preview with export if needed sealed the deal for me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After 80 days I had 1294 md notes. Each of them linked to a hierarchy, determined by their filename. The entire vault and configurations (to setup and use it anywhere) were saved in the repo and were versioned daily. Moreover every 10 minutes any changes were backed up to github. In the end, all I had to do was write notes, linking and hierarchy was handled by Dendron, history and backup was handled by git.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;notes&#x2F;intro&#x2F;dendron-notes-intro.png&quot; alt=&quot;dendron&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was looking for a tool to switch and while I was using Dendron, I read and thought about note taking and various &lt;em&gt;tools&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;: like obsidian, notion, evernote, etc, and methods: like zettlekasten, para, bullet journaling etc.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will share my thoughts and my current system of note taking in &lt;a href=&quot;..&#x2F;&quot;&gt;these few posts&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (another 3 probably). The first few will be about the tools and strategies that exist for note taking. In the last post I will describe and explain my own note taking system.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TLDR for the three posts:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note taking by itself is just a dump of ideas, to utilize that dump to do something productive is the most important part. The total output of the notes depends not only on the method used to store the notes but also the quality of what is being stored. You are what you eat, and in this case, you get what you put in.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The explanations will be discussed in the posts that follow.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Glorious Endgame</title>
		<published>2021-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/glorious-endgame/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/glorious-endgame/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;cover-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;cover.png&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;desc&quot;&gt;
    My endgame
  &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently switched to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;manjaro.org&#x2F;download&#x2F;#i3&quot;&gt;Manjaro i3&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. And so far it has been my best experience with linux. I took my experience from customizing and tweaking ubuntu throughout the years into the final &amp;quot;endgame&amp;quot; setup I have now. And I have no intentions of switching things soon. Here is a showcase of my setup and some discussion on the things I discovered during the process.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will cover customizations and workflows that I use with the current setup. I am welcome to all suggestions. Let&#x27;s begin!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rice&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&amp;quot;Rice&amp;quot; is a word that is commonly used to refer to making visual improvements and customizations on one&#x27;s desktop.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-customize&quot;&gt;Why customize&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don&#x27;t ask why, we ask why not.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few things in life that you didn&#x27;t know you wanted and you can&#x27;t live without after you have experienced them. For some, myself included, ricing is one such thing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most popular thing is not necessarily the best one. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you use your computer for more than just web browsing, investing some time to make the experience better visually and functionally can go a long way.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In process of customization, you may discover ways of using and controlling your computer and applications that you didn&#x27;t even fathom could exist.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everything comes free. You pay for the ability to customize with time. To have a desktop that you can be proud of, to have a desktop that looks so good that it inspires you to do stuff, you have to sacrifice time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;philosophy-of-customization&quot;&gt;Philosophy of Customization&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minimalism is not a lack of something. It’s simply the perfect amount of something. — Nicholas Burroughs&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are the guidelines I strive for when I have to customize:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It should match the overall theme.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dark mode &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Light Mode.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only show what is required all the time, all the time.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There should be one way to do things and that should be either:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Fastest way or&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Easiest way&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keyboard &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Mouse.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I fear not the man who has practiced 10,000 kicks once, but I fear the man who has practiced one kick 10,000 times. - Bruce Lee&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There might be 10,000 ways to do something, for example, open an application, play music, browse files, etc. But you have to choose the method that suits you and stick to it. With time you will master that way such that it will become second nature to you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You shouldn&#x27;t fight your desktop, you should harmonize with it. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You shouldn&#x27;t change yourself, you should change the desktop.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;window-manager&quot;&gt;Window Manager&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people use the default &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Desktop_environment&quot;&gt;Desktop Environment&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (DE) that comes with their linux distro. They change the widget&#x2F;icon themes and the wallpapers and call it a day. Which is totally fine. That is how popular DEs, such as Gnome, are designed to be used. Everything a normal user needs is packed in with few theming choices for the adventurous. Gnome isn&#x27;t meant to be heavily customized, it is a &amp;quot;use what you get&amp;quot; system. There is even a petition by GTK app developers to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;stopthemingmy.app&#x2F;&quot;&gt;stop theming altogether&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other end of the spectrum are &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Window_manager&quot;&gt;Window Managers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (WM). It is purely responsible for controlling the layout, positioning, and styling of window borders. It&#x27;s pointless to explain the benefits of WM over a DE here if you don&#x27;t try out a WM yourself. It is much like explaining VR, you won&#x27;t get it unless you try it out yourself. If you have Ubuntu installed you can try this &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=j1I63wGcvU4&quot;&gt;youtube tutorial for i3wm&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I use a variant of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;i3wm.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;i3&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; called &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;Airblader&#x2F;i3&quot;&gt;i3-gaps&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which allows for gaps between the windows.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do decide to try out a WM you will have to spend time learning it in the beginning. WMs are not the usual point and click tools most of us are used to. It will take time to get used to the keybindings. But once you do, navigating through windows and workspaces will be a breeze. You will be able to do almost everything via a keyboard.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;i3wm&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; is a tiling window manager, which means that new windows when opened don&#x27;t overlap the existing window, rather the space is split and the new one takes half of it. This way, there is no overlap and everything is visible at once. You use workspaces, somewhat like multiple desktops to have many more windows open at a given amount of time. Each workspace can have any amount of windows and have any layout.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be said that using a WM is more of a change in the user experience, the way you interact with the software than UI. The UI is up to you. Customize it as heavily or as lightly as only you want. i3wm looks terrible in its default bare-bones state:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;glorious-endgame&#x2F;i3-default.png&quot; alt=&quot;i3 default pic&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, you can also start with a pre-configured version, for example, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;manjaro.org&#x2F;download&#x2F;#i3&quot;&gt;Manjaro i3&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, an Arch-based distro that comes prepackaged with i3-gaps, with a nice default theme and basic creature comforts. It looks like:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;glorious-endgame&#x2F;manjaro-default.png&quot; alt=&quot;Manjaro i3 Default&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you can go further to customize just about everything on it like the setup I have:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;glorious-endgame&#x2F;my-setup.png&quot; alt=&quot;My Setup&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the clean empty desktop:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;glorious-endgame&#x2F;empty-desktop.png&quot; alt=&quot;Empty desktop&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some go even further. You don&#x27;t have to limit yourself to a specific WM. &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;dwm.suckless.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;DWM&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, for example, is built to be extended and compiled by the user, so you can go to the code level and write specific functionality that you want for yourself. You can find several examples, of beautiful setups at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.reddit.com&#x2F;r&#x2F;unixporn&#x2F;&quot;&gt;r&#x2F;unixporn&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stick to the i3-gaps variant myself for the following reasons:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is one of the most popular of the window managers so getting support and configuration files for it is easier than others.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is small in size and fast.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is a tiling WM and supports flexible layouts including Tiling, Floating, Tabbed, etc. I mostly stick to tiling.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some things might be better in more obscure WMs, but the tradeoff between switching and setting them up is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; offset by the benefits they offer. I am currently very content with i3.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another noticeable feature of i3 is the lack of window decoration. This saves the vertical space consumed by the title bar. You always know from the application itself what the application is, so the title is useless, and since the operations to manage windows are handled with keystrokes, the close button is not needed. And the minimize maximize buttons are useless for a tiling WM.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from window layout and management, you need a way to start applications. I use the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;davatorium&#x2F;rofi&quot;&gt;rofi&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; launcher, and it looks like this:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;glorious-endgame&#x2F;rofi.png&quot; alt=&quot;Rofi&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that is the only way I open apps. You can search for the app and hit enter which will open the highlighted app. Opening stuff through rofi is extremely fast once you get used to it. There are predefined shortcuts in Manjaro i3 for browser and file explorer (&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;wiki.archlinux.org&#x2F;index.php&#x2F;PCManFM&quot;&gt;pcmanfm&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;)  and I only use the file explorer shortcut.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bar at the bottom is &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;polybar&#x2F;polybar&quot;&gt;polybar&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. On the left side, it displays the opened workspaces and highlights the current workspace. On the center is the spotify song controls (discussed later), on the right are volume, storage, battery, and time indicators with the system tray icons at the end. Some people display current stats of CPU RAM etc on their polybar but I don&#x27;t because I don&#x27;t need that all the time. If you are wondering, yes the polybar is also hide-able!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;firefox&quot;&gt;Firefox&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step in customization is the browser. Chances are it is your most used software. So it does help to customize it as you will spend your time here more than anywhere else.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I riced my &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.mozilla.org&#x2F;en-US&#x2F;firefox&#x2F;&quot;&gt;firefox&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for an extremely minimal experience. In its default state it looks like this:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;glorious-endgame&#x2F;ffx-newtab.png&quot; alt=&quot;Firefox newtab small&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where is the navigation bar? How do you enter URL? What about bookmarks?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;glorious-endgame&#x2F;ffx.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Firefox use&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The above image is a gif, watch the action!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But where is the setting to tweak this? It is not a setting in firefox. You have to customize firefox&#x27;s interface via CSS. The tabbar, navbar, etc are rendered from HTML, thus their appearance and functionality can be changed. You can head over to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.reddit.com&#x2F;r&#x2F;FirefoxCSS&#x2F;&quot;&gt;r&#x2F;FirefoxCSS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to see what people have been able to do with it. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yes, it is not available in any chrome based browser as of now because almost all of them use Native C&#x2F;C++ for the browser UI, making it near impossible to customize.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why no bookmark bar? What about icons in newtab to open the most used websites? Since the address-bar can be used to search the web, the history, and the bookmarks, there is no need to have a separate bookmarks tabbar, just search for it in the address-bar itself! and if you don&#x27;t find it, the same term can then be searched on the web!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is this better than the standard look&#x2F;UI? It saves vertical space. I see more of the website than the browser. Also, no one looks at the navbar unless they are already going to interact with it. You can either show it while hovering over the tabbar or use keyboard shortcuts to focus the address-bar. And opening a newtab automatically focuses the addressbar.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, I open new tabs rather than browse in a single tab, this way I can branch off and keep stuff in the tabbar that I may deal with later. This does consume more memory but is easier to navigate and I don&#x27;t get in trouble unless I have 70, 80+ tabs with other apps open as well. Also opened tabs are a way of handling tasks, each tab is open for something. And once that something is done, it is closed. If that something has to be delayed, the tab can remain open, and since I restore my browser sessions, the next time I open the browser I get all the previously opened tabs.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The newtab is the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;tabliss.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;tabliss&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; extension which has been customized with a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;xypnox&#x2F;dotfiles&#x2F;blob&#x2F;master&#x2F;wallpapers&#x2F;newtab.png&quot;&gt;background&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; I made specifically for the newtab. The font on the tab is &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;indestructibletype.com&#x2F;Jost.html&quot;&gt;Jost&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from the key browser UI customizations, I have &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;openstyles&#x2F;stylus&quot;&gt;stylus&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; customizations for several websites to match the overall desktop theme. For example, here is twitter and youtube:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;glorious-endgame&#x2F;twitter.png&quot; alt=&quot;Twitter&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;glorious-endgame&#x2F;yt.png&quot; alt=&quot;Youtube&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;typora&quot;&gt;Typora&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My writing weapon of choice: &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;typora.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Typora&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I take all my notes in markdown. No, I don&#x27;t take notes of my physics classes, I take notes of everything else. Tech, programming, aesthetics, design, etc. All the stuff I write, blogs, poems, ideas, etc are first written on Typora and then migrated to their respective places. Here is how this paragraph looks while I edit it on Typora!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;glorious-endgame&#x2F;typora-para.png&quot; alt=&quot;Paragraph screenshot&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is all I see when I type. I mostly use Typora in fullscreen for a nice distraction-free feel. With the combination of minimalism and a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.reddit.com&#x2F;r&#x2F;MechanicalKeyboards&#x2F;&quot;&gt;mechanical keyboard&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, I can trick myself into thinking that the laptop is just an editing&#x2F;writing machine, a modern typewriter so to speak.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;glorious-endgame&#x2F;typora-sidebar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Typora Sidebar&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there is the sidebar, which when opened with a folder, lists all the files in a nested format. I have themed it so that it fades away and only focuses when hovered over. Minimal af.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theme for Typora is &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;xypnox&#x2F;xydark-typora&quot;&gt;xydark&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;spotify&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.spotify.com&#x2F;us&#x2F;download&#x2F;linux&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Spotify&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: The de facto music player!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;glorious-endgame&#x2F;spotify.png&quot; alt=&quot;Spotify&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khanhas&#x2F;spicetify-cli&quot;&gt;Spicetify&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; it matches my overall &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;xypnox&#x2F;dotfiles&#x2F;tree&#x2F;master&#x2F;spicetify&#x2F;Themes&#x2F;xydark&quot;&gt;theme&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and looks pretty rad. Apart from the basic spotify player, I also have the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;xypnox&#x2F;dotfiles&#x2F;blob&#x2F;946cff63cc6378fad1f1af01c8191cd9ca0d461b&#x2F;polybar&#x2F;config#L384-L412&quot;&gt;spotify module&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; at the center of my polybar which controls the playback from any workspace. When the text is longer than a specified length, it even does a marquee scroll reminiscent of the old LED displays:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;glorious-endgame&#x2F;spotify-module.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Spotify Module&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The above image is a gif, watch the action!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from the visual details, I have also mapped the media controls of the keyboard to spotify play, pause, etc.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;alacritty-zsh-prezto&quot;&gt;Alacritty &#x2F; Zsh &#x2F; prezto&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the benefits of using a tiling window manager is the ability to have several windows side by side. And the most opened window for a linux user is the terminal. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;alacritty&#x2F;alacritty&quot;&gt;alacritty&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as my terminal emulator for two reasons: It is fast, one of the fastest available terminals, and its configuration is a straightforward YAML file. There are more stripped-down terminals such as &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;wiki.archlinux.org&#x2F;index.php&#x2F;Rxvt-unicode&quot;&gt;URXVT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; but they are a pain to tweak and get just right.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;glorious-endgame&#x2F;alacritty.png&quot; alt=&quot;Terminal Alacritty&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the shell I use &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.zsh.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;zsh&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which by itself is quite powerful. Many who use zsh use &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ohmyz.sh&#x2F;&quot;&gt;oh-my-zsh&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on top to give it that extra horsepower, I use an alternative, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;sorin-ionescu&#x2F;prezto&quot;&gt;prezto&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I like prezto because it is more stripped, hence faster than oh-my-zsh and its default shell prompt is just amazing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever you use with zsh, oh-my-zsh or prezto, what you definitely want to do is enable &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;zsh-users&#x2F;zsh-autosuggestions&quot;&gt;zsh-autosuggestions&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It will save you a ton of time and make using the terminal a very enjoyable experience.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;vscode&quot;&gt;VSCode&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only editor that I use at the moment. The entire color scheme of my system is inspired by the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;material-theme.site&#x2F;&quot;&gt;material ocean dark&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; theme of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;code.visualstudio.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;VSCode&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. With the transparency and a few running terminals at the side the usual layout looks like this:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;glorious-endgame&#x2F;vscode.png&quot; alt=&quot;VSCode&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I need more than two terminals, for example when also running the backend with frontend, and accessing the database, I group my terminals in another workspace and let VSCode have the full space of the screen.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VSCode has a zen mode which I was never excited to try out. The default UI of VSCode is already pretty minimal and I didn&#x27;t want the hassle of switching modes back and forth to do anything other than editing. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have setup &lt;code&gt;Mod + Tab&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; as a keybinding in i3 to switch to the last opened workspace. This makes web development convenient as I can quickly switch between the VSCode workspace and the browser with a consistent keystroke. This can be used in other scenarios that require frequent switching between two workspaces.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;telegram&quot;&gt;Telegram&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;desktop.telegram.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Telegram&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is my main tool for messaging because I use it for everything other than messaging. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;glorious-endgame&#x2F;telegram.png&quot; alt=&quot;Telegram&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the only decent-looking, less resource-hungry app that can run in the background and has decent sync with the mobile app. Also, it is customizable af! Here is my &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;addtheme&#x2F;elIs3i0CQbGoD1nM&quot;&gt;telegram theme&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on desktop (&lt;em&gt;Of course these are not the recent chats&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;):&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;basic-amenities&quot;&gt;Basic Amenities&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have added a little transparency to some of the applications such as: Typora, Spotify, VSCode, pcmanfm, etc via &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;wiki.archlinux.org&#x2F;index.php&#x2F;Picom&quot;&gt;picom&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I have preset keybindings for full screen and rectangular selection screenshots. You can checkout &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;resurrecting-open-source-projects&#x2F;scrot&quot;&gt;scrot&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;naelstrof&#x2F;maim&quot;&gt;maim&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for your screen-capture use case. For gif recording, checkout &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;phw&#x2F;peek&quot;&gt;peek&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The widget on the desktop is a slightly tweaked version of a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;xypnox&#x2F;dotfiles&#x2F;tree&#x2F;master&#x2F;conky&quot;&gt;conky&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that comes preinstalled with Manjaro i3. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;clementtsang&#x2F;bottom&quot;&gt;bottom&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for process management and system monitoring. Here are a bunch of terminals with gaps increased for aesthetics:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;glorious-endgame&#x2F;terminals.png&quot; alt=&quot;Terminal Beauty&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-fault-in-our-dotfiles&quot;&gt;The fault in our dotfiles&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How wonderful the world of ricing is? Full of rainbows and sunshine. But it isn&#x27;t perfect. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several problems with my current setup:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Firefox in fullscreen mode doesn&#x27;t hide the tabbar.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The icons of the system tray applet are hard to customize.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The font of my choice, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;be5invis&#x2F;Iosevka&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Iosevka&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, due to its narrow width, has small nerd font characters.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;polybar&#x27;s padding with single app open looks imperfect. (In a perfect world padding would only be there if more than two apps are open in a single workspace)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The startup of i3, even though fast is still jarring, a smooth fade or growing animation, as found in Gnome would have been nice.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My current file manager, pcmanfm doesn&#x27;t support custom icons.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brightness controls are usable but not yet mapped to the external keyboard.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Typora is sexy but has no git support, I would have liked to browse the history of documents inside Typora itself. (VSCode can be helpful here)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you hear a voice within you say &lt;em&gt;you cannot customize&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, then by all means customize and that voice will be silenced.”&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
― Vimcent WM van Gtk&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;xypnox&#x2F;dotfiles&quot;&gt;My dotfiles&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.reddit.com&#x2F;r&#x2F;unixporn&#x2F;&quot;&gt;r&#x2F;unixporn&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; - The temple of ricing. Check the sub sidebar for further resources.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.reddit.com&#x2F;r&#x2F;FirefoxCSS&#x2F;&quot;&gt;r&#x2F;FirefoxCSS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; - The place for Firefox customizations&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;darkreader.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;darkreader&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; - make stuff dark.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Culture 2020</title>
		<published>2021-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/culture-2020/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/culture-2020/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;cover-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;cover.png&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;desc&quot;&gt;
    My year in Culture - 2020.
  &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year I have read several books, watched some movies, and listened to a lot of songs; here is a roundup of my favorite ones.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Maria Popova has put aptly in her roundup:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not and have never been a reviewer of books — a person who surveys the landscape of literature with the goal of evaluating its features. I am and have always been a solitary sojourner who relishes curious excursions hither and thither, guided by a thoroughly subjective inner compass, wandering the wilderness of words by pleasant deviations from the common trail.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are my footsteps.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not a reviewer either, each item presented here is content that I have enjoyed. That doesn&#x27;t imply that you will like it too. Moreover, nothing in this article is objective. I will try not to write long terse reviews as there are better, more experienced, and specialized people writing reviews for a living that can be found with a quick search.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that this article contains are recommendations and my comments on them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;books&quot;&gt;Books&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have read a lot of books this year. Goodreads shows 30, but it&#x27;s 29, due to a bug Goodreads counted one book twice. I am not going to cover all the books I read, they are too many, and I am a lame reviewer. Here are 5 of the good ones and one book to stay away from, because, it is also important to &lt;em&gt;isolate&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; yourself from harmful substances, as we have aptly learned this year.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-moon-is-a-harsh-mistress&quot;&gt;1. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.goodreads.com&#x2F;book&#x2F;show&#x2F;16690.The_Moon_Is_a_Harsh_Mistress&quot;&gt;Moon is a Harsh Mistress&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book is about a coup and revolution, it is more philosophical and political than you might expect, given it falls in the sci-fi genre. There are insights every now and then. The plot is tight enough to keep you on your toes and yet give you the time to consider the ideas discussed in the book yourself.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read it slow and steady and you will find the treasure buried within these pages.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-inspector-matadeen-on-the-moon&quot;&gt;2. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.goodreads.com&#x2F;book&#x2F;show&#x2F;3852305-inspector-matadeen-on-the-moon&quot;&gt;Inspector Matadeen on the Moon&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too many moony books? I promise this is the last one. And the moon story is one of a dozen selected pieces of satire by the legendary Harishankar Parsai. This is a rare book, mostly because it is an English translation of satires written 50-60 years ago. But it being so old makes it even more surprising, after decades of supposed &lt;em&gt;development&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; we are still stuck with the same corrupted politics, law, and justice system that we created when we gained independence. We have transformed from a meek populace consuming a movie in theaters to creating takataks on our &lt;em&gt;smartphones&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, with no real change in our mentality and outlook towards how our nation works.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s not all dark though. A few satires do indeed give a good laugh and end on a high note. But the grimness is what makes this book more relevant than ever.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-the-fitz-and-the-fool-trilogy&quot;&gt;3. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.goodreads.com&#x2F;series&#x2F;114440-fitz-and-the-fool&quot;&gt;The Fitz and the Fool trilogy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a recommendation for the dedicated and free. I started reading the works of Robin Hobb set in the Elderling realm when I started college and now, this year I finished the masterpiece saga with this trilogy. And it was worth it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robin Hobb is by far one of my favorite authors, with spectacular character development, intricate world-building, crisscrossed and overlapping plot, and a decent amount of philosophy tossed in. I have been with Fitz, the protagonist, since he was a child, till the end of the saga, which I won&#x27;t ruin here for you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I finally finished the epic, I contracted the emptiness that often comes after finishing a great book. As if you have lost an old friend. But credit given where it is due, the way the entire saga pans out and finally ends is extremely satisfying.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps they should have hired Robin Hobbs for writing the last season of Game of Thrones; Oh what miracles we might have witnessed!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-a-man-called-ove&quot;&gt;4. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.goodreads.com&#x2F;book&#x2F;show&#x2F;18774964-a-man-called-ove&quot;&gt;A Man called Ove&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ove is the kind of man that you can relate to in a busy boring world. What should you do when you think that the world is over? That there isn&#x27;t anything left in it worth living and you dying won&#x27;t change anything anyway.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book can be considered the answer to the inquiry by Albert Camus: “There is but one truly serious philosophical problem and that is suicide. Judging whether life is or is not worth living amounts to answering the fundamental question of philosophy.” So is living worth it? Read and find out. All I can say for sure is that reading this masterpiece is surely worth the time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-the-book-thief&quot;&gt;5. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.goodreads.com&#x2F;book&#x2F;show&#x2F;19063.The_Book_Thief&quot;&gt;The Book Thief&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This book will make you cry. This book will make your chest hurt. And it will do it while you are gripped in the story, thinking that everything will be finally all right. It will leave you battered and glad you are alive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will paint you a picture of what war was like inside Nazi Germany. How simple lives were tossed in a thunderstorm and how a small book thief tries to find safe harbor when there are none. Surprise! The narrator is the evergreen Death itself.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-one-to-avoid-the-alchemist&quot;&gt;The one to avoid: &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.goodreads.com&#x2F;book&#x2F;show&#x2F;18144590-the-alchemist&quot;&gt;The Alchemist&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know different people prefer different books. Just like music, where there are different tastes and various genres. And then there are books that will give you more worth out of your money if you tossed them in a fireplace, and enjoyed the warmth of the flames as they purified the pages, turning everything to black charcoal, unreadable, and for the better. This is one of those books.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote a rant on twitter for it, go read it if you need a more detailed thrashing of the book: &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;twitter.com&#x2F;xypnox&#x2F;status&#x2F;1277127044803858432&quot;&gt;PSA: Don&#x27;t read The Alchemist (A rant thread)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;tv-series-movies&quot;&gt;TV Series &#x2F; Movies&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the lack of a popular service such as Goodreads for movies and TV series, and my lack of interest in maintaining a record of what I have watched, I will just put some of the content that I can recall from the top of my head. Assuming of course that whatever that was left was either ancient or not worth remembering.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And since movies are much more consumable than books, I won&#x27;t go into detailed reviews.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Office - Best sitcom ever&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JoJo Rabbit - Fricking amazing. If you haven&#x27;t seen this, what are you doing?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Social Dilemma - A great look into our ever consuming behavior with social media apps.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Grand Budapest Hotel - A visual masterpiece&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loving Vincent - A movie created entirely with oil paintings. Each frame is a painting.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tenet - You already know it. In the future I mean.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avatar: The Last Airbender (TV series) - THE BEST THING EVER.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blackadder - A series of comedic sketches of important intervals in the History of England. Wonderful.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Queen&#x27;s Gambit - &lt;em&gt;The chess tv series&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Daniel Sloss&#x27;s X - An amazing standup routine, probably the best I watched this year.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Before Sunrise - A classic.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Borat pt 2. - Ah one of the hottest movies this year.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Handmaiden - I never watched a subbed film, and then this Korean flick sold me.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The perks of being a Wallflower - Another beautiful film.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;songs&quot;&gt;Songs?&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, have a playlist: &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;open.spotify.com&#x2F;playlist&#x2F;0684rk4NGsNZemX16lzpV1?si=HYl4cvVzRTu6ZJUZlmBv6w&quot;&gt;Best finds of 2020&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the size of the playlist: 180+ songs, I can&#x27;t discuss them here. I don&#x27;t recommend listening to every song, just use it as a 2020 radio mix.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-i-consume-stuff&quot;&gt;How I consume stuff.&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from books, I have stopped searching for good things to watch. There are too many movies, too many TV series, each with a distinct taste and story to tell. Too many. I have therefore restricted myself to content recommended to me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then I watch what has been recommended. I don&#x27;t do any research. If the content is worth it, it should have enough world-building and character development to stand on itself. If at any point it turns out to be boring or worthless, I stop. Not every book is meant to be finished, you can leave them in between. You can stop.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, I avoid myself from the great tides of one-hit wonder normie content waves. The &lt;em&gt;hyped cool thing consumed by everyone&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; is rarely ever cool.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then there is always the question of the best thing ever. Have you seen the best movie? Have I? No. The best movie hasn&#x27;t been made yet, and probably wouldn&#x27;t be made till centuries pass by. So, you are already missing out on the best thing ever, why not miss out on just a few more and put that time into consuming something more eccentric, rare, and specialized?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#x27;s hope we don&#x27;t blame the next year for our own mistakes and disasters like we did to the poor 2020.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Tech 2020</title>
		<published>2020-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/tech-2020/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/tech-2020/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;cover-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;cover.png&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;desc&quot;&gt;
    My year in Tech - 2020.

There will be a different post for culture 2020 as well.
  &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When someone starts writing a post about a tech product, it ends up being one of two things: Either an unbiased review or a very biased piece highlighting how the thing is &amp;quot;the best thing ever&amp;quot; &#x2F; &amp;quot;the worst thing ever&amp;quot;. And I promise you I will try my best not to do any of those in this post.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of this post discusses smartphones and what I think of them. Later on, there are a few other accessories discussed as well. Also, I will keep this post clear of the standard ramblings and thoughts of these products as I am sure you can find those on the internet anywhere.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;phone-pixel-4a&quot;&gt;Phone: &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.flipkart.com&#x2F;google-pixel-4a-just-black-128-gb&#x2F;p&#x2F;itm023b9677aa45d&quot;&gt;Pixel 4a&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best phone is the one in your hands. The numbers, the specs, they don&#x27;t matter. Because the only phone you can use is the one you have. You can fight with other people on which phone is better but if you lose, you aren&#x27;t going to buy the other&#x27;s phone, and neither will your opponent.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question of the best phone is relevant only when you have to buy a new one. When you have to look at your budget, and your priorities to decide what is best for you. The tech culture makes people forget about this. The geeks fight over which phone is better when they haven&#x27;t used either.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then it would seem that following trends in tech is stupid. It doesn&#x27;t seem to have any purpose. You only need to focus when you have to make a new purchase.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For most this assessment is justified. However, there are few, like myself, who take pride in the progress of technology, who are amazed when there&#x27;s a translucent display, or a foldable screen, or a telescopic lens, or an underscreen camera! All these are marvelous feats of engineering. And we like to follow these developments.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This doesn&#x27;t mean that we will purchase products with these features. Case in point, I got a Pixel 4a. It doesn&#x27;t have any of those cool things. It is disappointingly last gen.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has a single camera, no fast refresh rate, weak processor, no fancy front-facing cameras (just a boring punch-hole), and a plastic build. Yet, I love this phone. It doesn&#x27;t spark any joy when you talk about it in text, and it shouldn&#x27;t. It is not meant to crunch numbers or be a productivity powerhouse. It is meant to be a smartphone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My laptop is my &amp;quot;daily driver&amp;quot;. I do most of my &lt;em&gt;work&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; on it. I program, design, browse the web, take notes, watch YouTube, etc. on my laptop. All I ever use my phone is for:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being connected on the go (email, messaging services)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browsing Reddit and Twitter&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Camera&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reading Books&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spotify on the move&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#x27;s it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are power users out there who use their phones for... &lt;em&gt;I don&#x27;t know what&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. Gaming is better on PC, Productivity is better on PC, Web is better on PC. I don&#x27;t know why they need a phone unless they are &lt;em&gt;always&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; on the move and can&#x27;t bother with their laptops.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, given the small usecase for a phone, the best phone for me is the one that satisfies them as long as I own it. And this is the reason I avoid budget smartphones. Because they stop getting software updates.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I rock it naked. Without a cover or a screen protector. I accept the risk involved and enjoy the better ergonomics, lightness, and responsiveness that comes with the trade.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The camera is a joy to use. Here are a few shots I took and edited on the phone itself:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;tech-2020&#x2F;p1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Pixel photo 1&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;tech-2020&#x2F;p2.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Pixel photo 2&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;tech-2020&#x2F;p3.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Pixel photo 3&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;tech-2020&#x2F;p4.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Pixel photo 4&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These aren&#x27;t the photos a normal person would take, but these are the ones I enjoy because of their aesthetic.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the topic of whether the phones have taken us away from reality, here is a quote from &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.buzzfeednews.com&#x2F;article&#x2F;mathonan&#x2F;google-pixel-3-review-android&quot;&gt;a review of Pixel 3&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, written 2 years ago:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look around any city street and there we all are, with our heads down, walking past each other, unaware. I saw you in your car driving with your phone in your hand. I saw you at the playground looking at your phone while your child’s life passed you by. I saw you on your date, alone together.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, Pixel 4a is the perfect phone for me, not everyone. Go find your own best phone, it might be this or something entirely different.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I like:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The size - excellent single-handed usage.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The camera - near perfect.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software - clean and minimal, updated regularly.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I dislike:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Battery - but only slightly, esp. because I use it as a hotspot all the time.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any other custom launcher makes the animations a little janky and that is why I stick with the default launcher.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;mouse-logitech-g102-lightsync&quot;&gt;Mouse: &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.amazon.in&#x2F;gp&#x2F;product&#x2F;B08LT9BMPP&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Logitech G102 lightsync&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A decent mouse so far! I didn&#x27;t plan on getting a new one but after a few furious sessions of Krunker my old mouse started to show its age. Hence, I had to shell out for yhis one.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I like:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weight - It&#x27;s lighter than my previous mouse&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The lights - RGBeeee&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shape - Ergonomic and minimal&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I dislike:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configurability on Linux is a little broken, Pipper detects three LEDs as a single one.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;earphones-kz-zst&quot;&gt;Earphones: &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.amazon.in&#x2F;gp&#x2F;product&#x2F;B01N5CPXLU&#x2F;&quot;&gt;KZ ZST&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah if there was a heaven, it would probably sound like this.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These single-handedly justify a Spotify premium account. They convince me to listen to songs at a higher bitrate on Spotify; rather than the compressed crap on YouTube. (YouTube music has 256kbps bitrate and Spotify has 320kbps. YouTube videos have a bitrate of 192kbps.) And before you say that you don&#x27;t notice the difference in audio quality, it is because you aren&#x27;t using a good enough pair of earphones.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of anything on this post, this is the only one I recommend. It is for everyone, at least for those who haven&#x27;t yet sacrificed their headphone jacks for a worse and more expensive wireless audio experience.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I like:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sound Quality - Heavenly&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build quality - Very nice&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cable&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I dislike:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;None till now!&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;monitor-dell-p-series-24-inch&quot;&gt;Monitor: &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.amazon.in&#x2F;gp&#x2F;product&#x2F;B07F8XZN69&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Dell P Series 24-inch&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of the pandemic I had to leave this at college and it has been ~6 months since I last used it. And therefore my views of this monitor have dulled with time and I don&#x27;t seem to value it as much as I did when I used to use it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I like:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The size is perfect&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The design is nice&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I dislike:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Color accuracy compared to my laptop is bad&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have noticed myself in the past searching the internet on something that I will&#x2F;have purchased, and only reading reviews that reinforce the views I have already formed. Lately though, I have realized that it won&#x27;t get me anywhere. I will purchase the product no matter what I watch if I stick with my biases. So, what I do now is only look at the negative reviews for deal-breaking issues. These give me an idea of what to be worried about.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully I will make more informed decisions in 2021.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Custom Spotify Covers</title>
		<published>2020-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/custom-spotify-covers/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/custom-spotify-covers/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;cover-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;cover.png&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;desc&quot;&gt;
    A few covers, discussed in detail below.
  &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started creating covers for my Spotify Playlists earlier this year. It started as a fun thing to make the playlists look cool and relatable and transitioned into a tradition.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using custom images isn&#x27;t anything new, but not many create&#x2F;edit the images specifically to use as covers. Adding the name of the playlist is one of the things that separates just an image from a cover specifically for that playlist.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;managing-music&quot;&gt;Managing Music&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How the covers are created needs a discussion on what the covers are being created for. And this means a discussion on how I manage my music i.e. what songs I put together in a playlist.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always keep one &lt;em&gt;primary playlist&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; that contains all songs that I have recently listened to, that I would like to listen to again. All the songs from YouTube, Spotify&#x27;s radio, soundtracks of the content I am binging, songs posted on music forums, shared by friends, etc. go into this playlist. I use this playlist as background music while doing any work and also for casual free-time listening.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This can not go on forever, as the playlist increases in size, I create a new one. And the new one becomes the &lt;em&gt;current&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; primary playlist. Thus, I have a current playlist and a set of previous playlists with the &lt;em&gt;on loop&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; songs of that time. It forms a nice historic record of what I was listening to at a given point in time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started naming the playlists with year and version as &lt;em&gt;YYYYxV&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, for January 2020 it was 2020x1, or in other words, the first playlist of 2020. This trend continued till March after which Quarantine happened. When I started, I was hopeful, so I had a single playlist named Corona. But then the lockdown got extended and the next versions came automatically, CoronaX2, CoronaX3, etc. And now, I am on the 16th playlist &lt;em&gt;XD&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. (&lt;em&gt;And sadly there is no end in sight!&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some obvious flaws with this approach, almost all of the songs in the playlists are different. There is rarely a theme connecting all the songs together. Therefore, finding songs and playing them on &lt;em&gt;occasions&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; becomes a chore of remembering when you used to listen to a song and locating that playlist accordingly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To alleviate this, I have also started making thematic playlists. These are themed with &lt;em&gt;playing opportunities&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, specific scenarios in which I may play a song. I had a couple of these earlier but they were mostly bassy-bangers for parties. I don&#x27;t put much effort into thematic playlists right now, because the lockdown hasn&#x27;t presented any good &lt;em&gt;playing opportunities&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these out of the way, let us discuss the general method of how I create the covers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-process&quot;&gt;The Process&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I usually start by selecting a theme I am going for. Thematic playlists already have a theme for them. For chronological playlists, the theme for these becomes whatever is going on in my life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a theme decided, I head on to Unsplash and choose an image that I can use as the backbone for the cover design. I look for anything that is visually distinct and can suit the square aspect ratio.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the image selected, I use Figma to try out a few variations of typography and gradients, sometimes overlay filters, shadows, and abstract shapes, etc. I use a 1200x1200 square for the cover size and group all elements together. After a few more minutes of tweaking and testing, I export the image as JPEG (Spotify for some reason doesn&#x27;t support PNG).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This whole exercise from choosing a theme to a final cover image usually takes me about 15 minutes. I limit the time I spend on tweaking and try to finish a cover as soon as possible. As it is for my personal use, I don&#x27;t have to obsess too much on the overall quality as I only have to please myself, &lt;em&gt;no one else&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-covers&quot;&gt;The covers&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;coronax3&quot;&gt;CoronaX3&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;custom-spotify-covers&#x2F;CoronaX3.png&quot; alt=&quot;CoronaX3&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We start our journey with X3, the first custom cover I made that wasn&#x27;t just an image. I found the image on Unsplash, with the difference that it has the X3. Specifying that it is the cover of the CoronaX3 playlist. The background image is self-explanatory!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;coronax4&quot;&gt;CoronaX4&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;custom-spotify-covers&#x2F;CoronaX4.png&quot; alt=&quot;CoronaX4&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A bit more hopeful, a bit too complex.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; When I made this cover, I was viewing it in Figma, full-on zoomed to a large proportion. Thus, I used detail that was illegible at the size it was going to be displayed on Spotify, a meager 220px square. That is why the highlighted text visible at a large size is unreadable on Spotify. This was a guiding lesson and other covers were made with the actual size in mind.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;ghazals&quot;&gt;Ghazals&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;custom-spotify-covers&#x2F;Ghazals.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ghazals&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In between the quarantine, a friend of mine shared with me a long YouTube playlist of Ghazals. I took some of what I heard there and some that I had listened to earlier and put them into this playlist. For the visuals, I looked for something that resonated with &lt;em&gt;sufi, elegant, peaceful.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; The playful notch of Z adds a little style to the rather simple typography.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;coronax5&quot;&gt;CoronaX5&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;custom-spotify-covers&#x2F;CoronaX5.png&quot; alt=&quot;CoronaX5&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This heart-shaped image caught my eye as soon as I saw it. This image was crying out to be a cover for a playlist and it became the cover of CoronaX5. If you asked an English teacher to write out the meaning of this image, you will get perhaps a trilogy of thick novels.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is simpler, it&#x27;s just a paper heart tearing itself apart.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;classical-melodies&quot;&gt;Classical Melodies&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;custom-spotify-covers&#x2F;Classical_Melodies.png&quot; alt=&quot;Classical Melodies&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was a kid, with barely any sense of the world, my parents owned a cassette player and I heard most of the Hindi Classics on that player. Which is why the cover of this playlist is a cassette.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;broken&quot;&gt;Broken&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;custom-spotify-covers&#x2F;Broken.png&quot; alt=&quot;Broken&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a playlist that is broken.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vinyl is an image and the shadow is added in Figma. The fonts just match the feel of broken songs.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;coronax6&quot;&gt;CoronaX6&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;custom-spotify-covers&#x2F;CoronaX6.png&quot; alt=&quot;CoronaX6&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depicting the extended usage of screens and social media, this cover consists of the typical quarantining human of that time. Also, the way 6 fits in the curve of the neck is just beautiful.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;coronax7&quot;&gt;CoronaX7&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;custom-spotify-covers&#x2F;CoronaX7.png&quot; alt=&quot;CoronaX7&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah, this was made during the part of my internship where I worked from 9 in the morning till about 9 in the night. And all of it was mostly code. That is why it is all code and evokes the same overwhelming feeling that you get with a similar schedule.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;farmhouse&quot;&gt;Farmhouse&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;custom-spotify-covers&#x2F;Farmhouse.png&quot; alt=&quot;Farmhouse&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A playlist for the songs that give you the old country feeling, even though I have never experienced it first hand. The background image was colorful but de-saturating it gave it a more peaceful look.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;coronax8&quot;&gt;CoronaX8&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;custom-spotify-covers&#x2F;CoronaX8.png&quot; alt=&quot;CoronaX8&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Confusion with the world and with myself in general. &lt;em&gt;Why is the world whizzing by and I am stuck at a standstill?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; The image has been given a green tint to get the matrix look. The font is also monospace for a similar feel.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;coronax9&quot;&gt;CoronaX9&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;custom-spotify-covers&#x2F;CoronaX9.png&quot; alt=&quot;CoronaX9&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A peaceful paradise. A calm beach and timeless lighthouse (&lt;em&gt;kinda&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;). Pastel colors, thin font. Relates to a few songs on the playlist and a liberated mood of that time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;nightsky&quot;&gt;Nightsky&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;custom-spotify-covers&#x2F;Nightsky.png&quot; alt=&quot;Nightsky&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait for the night, then find the open sky, put this on and enjoy!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A set of songs that are meant to be heard on an open sky of stars, gazing into the despair of infinity, wondering about life and the world simultaneously.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;coronax10&quot;&gt;CoronaX10&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;custom-spotify-covers&#x2F;CoronaX10.png&quot; alt=&quot;CoronaX10&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was looking for something else but when I saw the Jellyfish, I couldn&#x27;t resist. And looking at the cover, it does look dope, even though it doesn&#x27;t relate specifically to anything in the playlist. But who cares, my playlists, my choice!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;coronax11&quot;&gt;CoronaX11&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;custom-spotify-covers&#x2F;CoronaX11.png&quot; alt=&quot;CoronaX11&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I said &lt;em&gt;enough with the images&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, What can you do with just Figma? And the smooth gradients with an infinite mirror text was the response!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;beats&quot;&gt;Beats&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;custom-spotify-covers&#x2F;Beats.png&quot; alt=&quot;Beats&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A playlist of beats, a long long list of songs to jam to without any emotional overhead. The guitar was fiery red in the start but with a few gradients, it really shined in the blue-green tone. The only shame is that the details of the flame are not as visible on Spotify.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;coronax12&quot;&gt;CoronaX12&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;custom-spotify-covers&#x2F;CoronaX12.png&quot; alt=&quot;CoronaX12&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;How do you do, fellow kids?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; A weak attempt at a hip-hoppy downtown cover. Graffiti on the wall, night lights of the cars, brown alleys. Just a cover that could as well have been a cover of a rap album.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;coronax13&quot;&gt;CoronaX13&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;custom-spotify-covers&#x2F;CoronaX13.png&quot; alt=&quot;CoronaX13&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The philosopher. My favorite cover so far. The theme is philosophy as I was reading and watching a lot of content related to philosophy at that time. In the beginning, the cover was meant to be a head of Socrates with Blue and Red copies slightly shifted to give the effect of a printing error and introduce intrigue.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final result is even better, a few images of a philosopher deep in thought, overlapped for a jarring yet pleasing look. The text, the layers, the colors, aren&#x27;t precise still everything seems to fit together and work nicely.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;coronax14&quot;&gt;CoronaX14&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;custom-spotify-covers&#x2F;Coronax14.png&quot; alt=&quot;CoronaX14&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Office. The show I binged as if I would die tomorrow. It&#x27;s an amazing show, highly recommended! and it becomes the theme of this cover. Also because a few songs from the soundtrack make it to the playlist.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;coronax15&quot;&gt;CoronaX15&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;custom-spotify-covers&#x2F;CoronaX15.png&quot; alt=&quot;CoronaX15&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New phone, no image challenge.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now again, this cover doesn&#x27;t use any images, rather it uses the vector capabilities of Figma to hint the phone on the cover. It is very minimal, any more detail would have been hidden on Spotify&#x27;s small size. It is also one of the larger playlists!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;coronax16&quot;&gt;CoronaX16&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;custom-spotify-covers&#x2F;CoronaX16.png&quot; alt=&quot;CoronaX16&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tired! Tired of all the assignments and tests and what-nots!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was what I wanted to feel with the cover and the Koala truly does justice to the feeling. Monochrome adds another touch of class with increased letter spacing being the final detail to finish the cover.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-s-ahead&quot;&gt;What&#x27;s ahead?&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still make playlists and perhaps will continue to make the covers for them. And if there are enough of them, I will make another post sharing them too!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons I made this blog posts was that if I didn&#x27;t eventually I would have too many covers to discuss in a single post!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-parting-gift&quot;&gt;A parting gift&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have scrolled so far, I guess you deserve something for the effort!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here you go: &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=kc5X66kFIMg&quot;&gt;Novels - Rusty Clanton &amp;amp; doodleodle&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. A song I first listened to long ago and has recently revived itself as one of my absolute favorites. Sadly this version isn&#x27;t on Spotify.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you want any of these playlists, send me one of yours, we will trade!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Migrating to Zola</title>
		<published>2020-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/migrating-to-zola/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/migrating-to-zola/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;cover-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;cover.png&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;desc&quot;&gt;
    The two sides of the Yin and Yang combine to provide ultimate harmony!
  &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently migrated my &lt;em&gt;blag&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; from Hugo to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.getzola.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Zola&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I made my theme for this blog and it was a blast!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will discuss the why and the how in this post.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-why&quot;&gt;The Why?&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of features and ecosystem, Hugo trumps Zola any day. Then why did I switch?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-s-wrong-with-hugo&quot;&gt;What&#x27;s wrong with Hugo?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started using Hugo for the blog about 3 years ago. I used &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;minimo.netlify.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Minimo&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a minimalist, sleek and modern theme. It was one of the primary reasons why I started using Hugo in the first place. I could give it a unique look with minimal customization of typography and colors. And it worked, the blog loaded fast, looked beautiful, and worked nicely.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as time moved on, the author of the theme started adding features which were generally useful and nice to have, but useless for me. A few of those were search, widgets, translations, sidebar, etc. I had to disable several of these in the configuration. And with every update, there were always a few changes that required me to edit the config file even though I wasn&#x27;t going to use them anyway.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After several such continuous updates of useless features, I decided to fork the theme into a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;xypnox&#x2F;blag-theme&quot;&gt;custom one (which I named blag-theme)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Adding my mods directly to the theme simplified the &amp;quot;hacks&amp;quot; I had used earlier to customize the blog. But slowly it dawned on me that I wasn&#x27;t using even half of the features that were offered. And editing it to simplify the theme was painful, partly because of too many features and partly due to the theming and templating complexity of Hugo itself.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, I was satisfied. Even though it looked a mess behind the curtains, and even though I had given up on either simplifying or creating a new theme (in Hugo), the blog still looked fine and was readable&#x2F;usable for the end-user.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, these are modern times we live in. While working on the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;lttkgp.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;LTTKGP&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; project, my fav thing was the dark theme. It looked sick. And I wondered if I could have a dark theme for my blog as well. However, the monolith like templates got the better of me and I held off. There I was, wishing I could have a dark theme and there was Hugo, scaring me nuts with its complexity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it wouldn&#x27;t be an overstatement to say that Hugo&#x27;s current ecosystem makes it very hard for someone to create a new theme for scratch, or even significantly modify a theme without going through pages and pages of documentation; Almost like learning an entire &amp;quot;framework&amp;quot;. It is often the case that those starting with Hugo just stick to one of the pre-existing themes and don&#x27;t put any effort into customizing it, simply because it is too hard to customize.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the time when I created the blog in Hugo, it was all the rage. Almost everyone I knew personally used Hugo for their blogs. Then as time passed more &amp;quot;modern&amp;quot; SSGs were invented such as &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.gatsbyjs.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Gatsby&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;nextjs.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Next.js&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I disliked Gatsby because it felt too processed and complex for something so simple as a blog. I have given Next.js a try in my &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;poems.xypnox.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Poem Collection&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; but I didn&#x27;t find it exciting enough to switch over.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;enter-zola&quot;&gt;Enter Zola&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a few weeks ago, I was browsing the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;trending&#x2F;rust?since=daily&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Trending&amp;quot; page on GitHub&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and was looking at popular repositories, and there I found &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.getzola.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Zola&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a static site generator written in &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.rust-lang.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Rust&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. As it happens with several projects, Zola was created long ago but I got to know about it now. Due to it being written in Rust and having a minimal approach to SSGs, it wasn&#x27;t as popular. And frankly, had I not fallen in love with rust earlier I would have also given it a pass.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With my recent exposure to the Rust ecosystem, I have formed a view that &lt;em&gt;the developers that are using rust &amp;quot;think&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;reason&amp;quot; about their applications a lot more than other languages&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. And I understand that this view may very well be wrong. This was my viewpoint when I discovered Zola, and I immediately dove in, skimming it&#x27;s docs and comparing how it approached a &amp;quot;Static Site Generator&amp;quot;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zola&#x27;s take on SSG is quite different from other tools such as Jekyll and Hugo.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It doesn&#x27;t have a plugin system.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; (At least as of now) Everything that matters, or what the author considers matters, is built in the single binary. It includes: Sass compilation, syntax highlighting, ToC, etc. And if you want to add others, just include the javascript libraries in the templates!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It&#x27;s rust, therefore it&#x27;s fast.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; Speed isn&#x27;t that much of an issue for small blogs such as this one, but still faster compilation means faster hot reloading in dev mode when you edit your themes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is intuitive.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; And even though it may not make much of a difference for those who have the time to sift through the documentation of other SSGs, it was a big deal for me. I don&#x27;t want to spend months reading documentation and configuring the website, especially a blog that probably won&#x27;t ever generate any revenue.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can look at the directory structure of this blog below and have a fairly good idea of what each folder is for:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;blag
├── content
│   ├── pages
│   └── posts
├── static
│   ├── css
│   ├── icon
│   └── images
├── sass
└── themes
    └── xyblag
        ├── sass
        ├── static
        └── templates
            ├── categories
            ├── shortcodes
            └── tags
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That above, is the entire directory structure, including the theme. Posts can have individual directories to store assets, but that doesn&#x27;t concern us.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For comparison, Here is the directory structure of Hugo that I used earlier with the theme for fairness (&lt;em&gt;feel free to skip through this code block&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;) :&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;blag
├── archetypes
├── content
│   ├── page
│   └── posts
├── static
│   ├── css
│   ├── icon
│   └── images
└── themes
    └── blag-theme
        ├── archetypes
        ├── data
        │   └── config
        │       └── default
        ├── exampleSite
        │   ├── content
        │   │   ├── authors
        │   │   ├── docs
        │   │   │   └── res
        │   │   ├── page
        │   │   └── tags
        │   │       ├── config
        │   │       └── og
        │   ├── data
        │   │   ├── authors
        │   │   ├── comments
        │   │   │   └── 33deba780bf80cacf2627abf7a22fec7
        │   │   └── config
        │   └── static
        │       ├── css
        │       ├── images
        │       └── js
        ├── i18n
        ├── images
        ├── layouts
        │   ├── _default
        │   ├── page
        │   ├── partials
        │   │   ├── comments
        │   │   │   └── staticman
        │   │   ├── data
        │   │   │   └── author
        │   │   ├── entry
        │   │   │   └── meta
        │   │   ├── extras
        │   │   ├── footer
        │   │   ├── head
        │   │   │   └── opengraph
        │   │   ├── header
        │   │   ├── list
        │   │   ├── nav
        │   │   │   └── menus
        │   │   ├── sidebar
        │   │   ├── svg
        │   │   └── widgets
        │   ├── shortcodes
        │   └── taxonomy
        ├── scripts
        ├── src
        │   ├── scripts
        │   │   └── search
        │   └── stylesheets
        │       ├── elements
        │       ├── extras
        │       │   ├── mixins
        │       │   └── variables
        │       ├── forms
        │       ├── hugo
        │       │   └── shortcodes
        │       ├── layouts
        │       │   ├── entry
        │       │   ├── others
        │       │   ├── sidebar
        │       │   └── widgets
        │       ├── navigation
        │       │   └── menus
        │       └── typography
        └── static
            ├── assets
            │   ├── css
            │   └── js
            └── images

&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good luck understanding that! (I couldn&#x27;t)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see with the above example the simplicity and sensibility of Zola. And it carries through to other aspects of its usage as well.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I used Hugo, I was so tired that I never dealt with the auto-deployment side of things. I manually generated the blog on my machine and pushed it to GitHub like a 19t- century peasant.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Zola, setting up auto-deployment was as easy as creating a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.getzola.org&#x2F;documentation&#x2F;deployment&#x2F;github-pages&#x2F;#github-actions&quot;&gt;Github Action&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the benefits of Zola, it&#x27;s simplicity, ease of use, intuitiveness, all batteries included, and a solid base of rust was enough for me to give it a spin. The auto-deployment was the cherry on the cake!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-how&quot;&gt;The How?&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I have raved long enough about Zola, how was the migrating experience? To sum it up, &lt;em&gt;smooth with a few hiccups&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Migrating a blog is like moving into a new home. You arrange all of your &lt;em&gt;furniture and appliances&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; (your posts), and decorate the house with &lt;em&gt;fancy wallpapers&#x2F;wall paint, curtains, etc.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; (themes) and hope that the &lt;em&gt;location&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; (permalinks) remains the same so that the old visitors can easily find their way when they come again.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-links-must-be-the-same&quot;&gt;The links must be the same&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making the permalinks the same is &lt;em&gt;very very important&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. If you change the links that initially pointed to the old posts you would be contributing to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Link_rot&quot;&gt;Link rot&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the people who may have referenced your posts would have broken links. And a visitor arriving at your blog would see the disgraceful 404 page! So your content&#x27;s links &lt;em&gt;must&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; be the same when you switch to a new SSG.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The link of my blog posts has the structure of &lt;code&gt;xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;&amp;lt;slug&amp;gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;.To achieve the same structure I put the markdown files in &lt;code&gt;content&#x2F;posts&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; with an &lt;code&gt;_index.md&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; file in the posts directory with:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;markdown&quot; class=&quot;language-markdown &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-markdown&quot; data-lang=&quot;markdown&quot;&gt;+++
transparent = true
redirect_to = &amp;quot;&amp;#x2F;&amp;quot;
+++
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;transparent&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; tells Zola that the posts in this directory are meant to be pushed one directory up so that they appear in the index list. And if someone visits the &lt;code&gt;&#x2F;posts&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; URL, they will be redirected to the homepage &lt;code&gt;&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The specific pages such as &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;about&#x2F;&quot;&gt;About&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;quotes&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Quotes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;why-xypnox&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Why xypnox&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; have configuration like:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;markdown&quot; class=&quot;language-markdown &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-markdown&quot; data-lang=&quot;markdown&quot;&gt;+++
title = &amp;quot;About&amp;quot;
path = &amp;quot;about&amp;quot;
template = &amp;quot;about.html&amp;quot;
+++

Markdown content of the page
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that when someone visits &lt;code&gt;&#x2F;about&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; path, they see the about page! And the template used to render is &lt;code&gt;about.html&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; which as defined in the theme, doesn&#x27;t have the comment section.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;configuration-is-easy&quot;&gt;Configuration is easy&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The configuration ideology of Zola is quite simple: &lt;em&gt;You opt-in for the things you need.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; And the only necessary variable in &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; is &lt;code&gt;base_url&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;! This approach makes it easier to understand and maintain your blog as you are only dealing with what you are using explicitly. This includes code highlighting, search index, sass compilation, feed generation, taxonomies, etc.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you start using a theme, some of the themes will require you to set up these variables such as taxonomies because the themes require them to render properly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;templating-is-solid&quot;&gt;Templating is solid&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zola uses the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;tera.netlify.app&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Tera&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; templating engine. It is inspired by Jinja and Django&#x27;s templating engine and therefore if you have prior experience with these, it will feel like home. And even if you are new, it is still simple enough to understand and use.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the code for the theme will be written as templates. You can always use pre-existing themes as a starting point. I used the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;zola-even.netlify.app&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Even theme&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as it was bare and its layout was similar to my previous Hugo based blog. Needless to say, the current theme is a significant step-up from the Even theme. Here is a screenshot of the theme I created:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;xypnox&#x2F;blag&#x2F;blob&#x2F;master&#x2F;themes&#x2F;xyblag&#x2F;screenshot.png?raw=true&quot; alt=&quot;Blag screenshot&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need to include any javascript files or other links, you can add them to the template. A tweak that I did to improve the loading performance was to put the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;slideout.js.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;slideout.js&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; script with the static files so that when the page loads it doesn&#x27;t do a request to another server just for a small javascript file.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sass-make-it-pop&quot;&gt;Sass: Make it pop&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The styling is handled via &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;sass-lang.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;SASS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and I love it. I have used SASS in a lot of my previous projects and I adore the variables, mixins, and nested styles. It just ends up making stylesheets more readable and maintainable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Even&amp;quot; theme had a great underline from center animation on menu links and in the Index and Taxonomy lists. I modified the animation to add a little glow with a thicker line and rounded corners.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, even though I liked the summaries in the original theme, I found it not as useful in my theme. Firstly, because to use the summaries you need to add a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;!-- more --&amp;gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; comment to specify where to break, and usually the summaries are not of similar length.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence, the current &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;&quot;&gt;index page&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; just has the post title and the category with the date. One unintended but happy consequence of removing the summaries is that people will open the article to view the full contents more often!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-want-it-darker&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;v0nmHymgM7Y&quot;&gt;You want it darker?&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven&#x27;t seen the dark mode yet, do it right now! You can use the switcher below:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;theme-switcher&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;theme-button&quot; onClick=&quot;toggleTheme()&quot;&gt;
        &lt;label for=&quot;cb1&quot;&gt;
            &lt;svg
                id=&quot;dayIcon&quot;
                style=&quot;enable-background:new 0 0 35 35;&quot;
                version=&quot;1.1&quot;
                viewBox=&quot;0 0 35 35&quot;
                x=&quot;0px&quot;
                xml:space=&quot;preserve&quot;
                xmlns:xlink=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.w3.org&#x2F;1999&#x2F;xlink&quot;
                xmlns=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.w3.org&#x2F;2000&#x2F;svg&quot;
                y=&quot;0px&quot;&gt;
                &lt;g id=&quot;Sun&quot;&gt;
                    &lt;g&gt;
                        &lt;path
                            d=&quot;M6,17.5C6,16.672,5.328,16,4.5,16h-3C0.672,16,0,16.672,0,17.5 S0.672,19,1.5,19h3C5.328,19,6,18.328,6,17.5z
                                M7.5,26c-0.414,0-0.789,0.168-1.061,0.439l-2,2C4.168,28.711,4,29.086,4,29.5
                                C4,30.328,4.671,31,5.5,31c0.414,0,0.789-0.168,1.06-0.44l2-2C8.832,28.289,9,27.914,9,27.5C9,26.672,8.329,26,7.5,26z M17.5,6
                                C18.329,6,19,5.328,19,4.5v-3C19,0.672,18.329,0,17.5,0S16,0.672,16,1.5v3C16,5.328,16.671,6,17.5,6z M27.5,9
                                c0.414,0,0.789-0.168,1.06-0.439l2-2C30.832,6.289,31,5.914,31,5.5C31,4.672,30.329,4,29.5,4c-0.414,0-0.789,0.168-1.061,0.44
                                l-2,2C26.168,6.711,26,7.086,26,7.5C26,8.328,26.671,9,27.5,9z M6.439,8.561C6.711,8.832,7.086,9,7.5,9C8.328,9,9,8.328,9,7.5
                                c0-0.414-0.168-0.789-0.439-1.061l-2-2C6.289,4.168,5.914,4,5.5,4C4.672,4,4,4.672,4,5.5c0,0.414,0.168,0.789,0.439,1.06 L6.439,8.561z
                                M33.5,16h-3c-0.828,0-1.5,0.672-1.5,1.5s0.672,1.5,1.5,1.5h3c0.828,0,1.5-0.672,1.5-1.5S34.328,16,33.5,16z
                                M28.561,26.439C28.289,26.168,27.914,26,27.5,26c-0.828,0-1.5,0.672-1.5,1.5c0,0.414,0.168,0.789,0.439,1.06l2,2
                                C28.711,30.832,29.086,31,29.5,31c0.828,0,1.5-0.672,1.5-1.5c0-0.414-0.168-0.789-0.439-1.061L28.561,26.439z M17.5,29
                                c-0.829,0-1.5,0.672-1.5,1.5v3c0,0.828,0.671,1.5,1.5,1.5s1.5-0.672,1.5-1.5v-3C19,29.672,18.329,29,17.5,29z M17.5,7
                                C11.71,7,7,11.71,7,17.5S11.71,28,17.5,28S28,23.29,28,17.5S23.29,7,17.5,7z M17.5,25c-4.136,0-7.5-3.364-7.5-7.5
                                c0-4.136,3.364-7.5,7.5-7.5c4.136,0,7.5,3.364,7.5,7.5C25,21.636,21.636,25,17.5,25z&quot;
                            style=&quot;fill-rule:evenodd;clip-rule:evenodd;&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
                    &lt;&#x2F;g&gt;
                &lt;&#x2F;g&gt;
            &lt;&#x2F;svg&gt;
        &lt;&#x2F;label&gt;
        &lt;input class=&quot;toggle&quot; id=&quot;cb1&quot; onClick=&quot;toggleTheme()&quot; type=&quot;checkbox&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
        &lt;label class=&quot;toggle-button&quot; for=&quot;cb1&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;label&gt;
        &lt;label for=&quot;cb1&quot;&gt;
            &lt;svg
                enable-background=&quot;new 0 0 100 100&quot;
                id=&quot;nightIcon&quot;
                version=&quot;1.1&quot;
                viewBox=&quot;0 0 100 100&quot;
                x=&quot;0px&quot;
                xml:space=&quot;preserve&quot;
                xmlns:xlink=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.w3.org&#x2F;1999&#x2F;xlink&quot;
                xmlns=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.w3.org&#x2F;2000&#x2F;svg&quot;
                y=&quot;0px&quot;&gt;
                &lt;path d=&quot;M96.76,66.458c-0.853-0.852-2.15-1.064-3.23-0.534c-6.063,2.991-12.858,4.571-19.655,4.571
                C62.022,70.495,50.88,65.88,42.5,57.5C29.043,44.043,25.658,23.536,34.076,6.47c0.532-1.08,0.318-2.379-0.534-3.23
                c-0.851-0.852-2.15-1.064-3.23-0.534c-4.918,2.427-9.375,5.619-13.246,9.491c-9.447,9.447-14.65,22.008-14.65,35.369
                c0,13.36,5.203,25.921,14.65,35.368s22.008,14.65,35.368,14.65c13.361,0,25.921-5.203,35.369-14.65 c3.872-3.871,7.064-8.328,9.491-13.246C97.826,68.608,97.611,67.309,96.76,66.458z&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
            &lt;&#x2F;svg&gt;
        &lt;&#x2F;label&gt;
    &lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt; &lt;&#x2F;center&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(The switcher is also located at the top menu bar, and in mobile, it is in the side-menu)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there it is, the &lt;em&gt;Dark Mode&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; in all its glory.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To add dark mode, I had to restructure the colors to use CSS variables so that I could simply change them whenever the theme switched at the base itself. This also meant that since I was always using the CSS variables, later updates would force me to take care of the dark mode, as I will not forget to add and change the variable in the dark mode as well!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few things to take into consideration while adding dark mode to your site:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does your site have elements that need more than color variables to switch the theme? For example, Wikipedia&#x27;s equations are rendered SVGs so it is harder to change its color.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The theme preference should be stored locally so that subsequent revisits have the same preference.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The theme should respect the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;developer.mozilla.org&#x2F;en-US&#x2F;docs&#x2F;Web&#x2F;CSS&#x2F;@media&#x2F;prefers-color-scheme&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;prefers-color-scheme&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; setting of the user if it can&#x27;t find the preference in the &lt;code&gt;localStorage&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When the site loads, it shouldn&#x27;t load the light theme or dark theme by default and then switch on detecting the user&#x27;s preference. This will make a flash of light before switching to the dark mode and vice versa.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These can be solved by including a little bit of Javascript just before the main content of the body. The trick here is that this bit of code is executed and only after it&#x27;s evaluation is the rest of the code executed. Here is the JS code that finds and sets the theme on the page-load of this blog:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot; class=&quot;language-javascript &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot; data-lang=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;(function initTheme() {
  let body = document.getElementsByTagName(&amp;#x27;body&amp;#x27;)[0];

  if (window.localStorage.getItem(&amp;#x27;theme&amp;#x27;) !== null) {
    if (window.localStorage.getItem(&amp;#x27;theme&amp;#x27;) === &amp;#x27;dark&amp;#x27;) {
      body.setAttribute(&amp;#x27;data-theme&amp;#x27;, &amp;#x27;dark&amp;#x27;);
    } else {
      body.setAttribute(&amp;#x27;data-theme&amp;#x27;, &amp;#x27;light&amp;#x27;);
    }
  } else {
    if (
      window.matchMedia &amp;amp;&amp;amp;
      window.matchMedia(&amp;#x27;(prefers-color-scheme: dark)&amp;#x27;).matches
    ) {
      body.setAttribute(&amp;#x27;data-theme&amp;#x27;, &amp;#x27;dark&amp;#x27;);
    }
  }
})();
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that switcher that comes in between this post? That is plain HTML copied from the theme code. Also, it triggers the same function that changes the theme.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;socially-appropriate-media-tags&quot;&gt;Socially appropriate: Media tags&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zola is so minimal that it doesn&#x27;t add any media tags, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ogp.me&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Opengraph&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;developer.twitter.com&#x2F;en&#x2F;docs&#x2F;twitter-for-websites&#x2F;cards&#x2F;overview&#x2F;abouts-cards&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, required to display nice previews when shared to social sites such as Facebook, Twitter, etc. (&lt;em&gt;And the &amp;quot;Even&amp;quot; theme didn&#x27;t have them either&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;). So, I had to add them myself, one set of tags for all the generic pages, and one for the posts.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another problem with the social tags is that even though Facebook will correctly parse the page and use an appropriate image for its card, twitter requires you to put a specific image URL in the meta tags. To solve this I added a new variable in the posts&#x27; configuration, &lt;code&gt;metadata_image&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, that stores the absolute path of the image that is used in social previews.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;them-comments&quot;&gt;Them Comments&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comments are an important part of the blog for me as they allow me to have a discourse with the people who are interested and excited by my posts. And preserving the old comments from the previous version was therefore important. Luckily, I used &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;disqus.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Disqus&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as the comment platform, and the great thing is that if the link to the posts is the same, Disqus shows the old comments!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding Disqus to Zola was a bit more complicated than others, still, it was simple enough. I had to copy the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;help.disqus.com&#x2F;en&#x2F;articles&#x2F;1717112-universal-embed-code&quot;&gt;universal embed code&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and put it in the template in the right place. In the initialization script, I used the template variables to fill the link and unique identifiers for the post and that was enough for the comments to show up successfully.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of theme support, when Disqus is set to the Auto theme, it automatically sets the correct theme depending on the font color passed to it. The problem is that the Disqus theme doesn&#x27;t change when the overall theme changes. So, to switch the Disqus theme as well, I have to reload Disqus on every theme change, so that you don&#x27;t have to reload the entire page to access Disqus with the correct theme.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;analytics-oh-no&quot;&gt;Analytics? Oh no.&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though I am interested in collecting analytics for my blog, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;consent.guide&#x2F;google-analytics-cookie-consent&#x2F;&quot;&gt;adding Google Analytics requires affirmative consent from the user&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. And adding a big-yucky-privacy-consent-popup when someone lands on a minimal blog page is just ugly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, the &lt;em&gt;aesthetic disadvantages&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; of adding a banner for consent far outweigh the &lt;em&gt;advantages of collecting data&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; which I may barely use. The blog posts I write aren&#x27;t monetized and if someone wants to communicate, or suggest a topic for a post, he or she can always comment or reach out via mail! (xypnox gmail com).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides, Google&#x27;s search console provides similar data about the popularity of my blog posts already, albeit only limited to the Google search results.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;deployment&quot;&gt;Deployment&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current blog uses a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;shalzz&#x2F;zola-deploy-action&quot;&gt;GitHub action&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to auto-deploy whenever a new commit is pushed to master. Setting up the deployment was easy and the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.getzola.org&#x2F;documentation&#x2F;deployment&#x2F;github-pages&#x2F;#github-actions&quot;&gt;steps mentioned in the documentation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are enough.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cool thing is that I can mark the &lt;code&gt;public&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; folder as ignored in git and I don&#x27;t ever commit any of the generated code in the &lt;del&gt;master&lt;&#x2F;del&gt; main branch. Also, to add a new article, I can just create a markdown file using mobile or any device by logging into GitHub on that machine.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-future-where-from-to-from-now&quot;&gt;The future: Where from to from now?&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though this blog has almost all the features I desire, there are still somethings to iron out:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Emoji Support&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Independent, decoupled Reusable theme&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highlighting of the current title in the Content sidebar&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content sidebar for mobile&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There may be more features coming but these are the major ones for now.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source code of the blog is available at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;xypnox&#x2F;blag&quot;&gt;xypnox&#x2F;blag&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in this theme do feel free to reach out. I will prioritize the decoupling of the theme based on other people&#x27;s interest in it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The Secret of Life</title>
		<published>2020-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/the-secret-of-life/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/the-secret-of-life/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There is no secret of life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First forgive yourself,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
of the mistakes that haunt you.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Then become what you always wanted to be,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Or try to be as close to it as possible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be humble and friendly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Receive what you get with open hands,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
And know the value of what you have,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
And try to share it too.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of all the versions of you,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Who might have been,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Be the best you could be.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compete with yourself,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Collaborate with everyone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Celebrate what you can, when you can, even when you can&#x27;t.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
For happiness and joy, need little reasons.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are responsible for yourself.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Be kind. Be brave.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If something doesn&#x27;t please you, change it.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
If a book is bad, stop reading.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
There is no time in life to be wasted on things we don&#x27;t like.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are too many books to read,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Too much to watch, too much to listen.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
You will never be able to do everything,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
know everything, be everything.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Don&#x27;t fret on missing out.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be patient.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Things take time to happen,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
And take your time doing things you love.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
For there is only so little of time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is nothing right or wrong,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
But thinking makes it so,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
So do what makes you sleep at night.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do what you love,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
And you won&#x27;t have to work at all.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life carries challenges we try to avoid,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
But it is better to deal with the inevitabilities,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
For they are bound to happen.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#x27;t waste time in questioning death,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
It shall come when it will,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
As no one knows what happens afterwards,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Focus on what you can do before.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Aim not to go to heaven, but make heaven around you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Believe, if you can&#x27;t otherwise.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
If you do believe in God, you should fiercely,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
For only God can save you.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
However, always believe in yourself,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Otherwise why will others.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speak but with caution,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
For your words carry as much importance&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
As your meaning.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put so much effort in what you do,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
That it becomes effortless.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anything can get better or worse,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Be careful what you wish for.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strive for wisdom than knowledge.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Forgive if you can and forget if you can&#x27;t.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Empathy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is hard to know whether to trust or not.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
It is harder to choose whom to trust.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
You can only know if someone is trustworthy&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
By trusting them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Know this, that humans are the best&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
and worst things you will ever meet.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Cherish the best, and forget the rest.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
There are too many humans to generalize.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
The only thing we have in common is that we are unique.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pain is what makes it real,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Or else it would all be a dream.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life is unfair is no reason for unfairness.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are all going to die one day,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Remember to live before you do too.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
There is no excuse for not living.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
To live is the secret of life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And never loose hope.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS. I am with you even when you are not.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Typography</title>
		<published>2019-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/typography/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/typography/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;cover-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;&amp;#x2F;blag&amp;#x2F;images&amp;#x2F;typography.png&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;desc&quot;&gt;
    Cover by xypnox
  &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Typography&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; is the art and technique of arranging type. It is the method used to make text readable, legible, beautiful and meaningful. Good typography is readable. No matter how stylish and polished your font is, if it isn&#x27;t readable no one is gonna &lt;em&gt;read&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beauty of type lies in its utility; prettiness without readability serves neither the author nor reader. - James Felici&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main way in which we style our texts is with fonts. Fonts are more or less a complete set of glyphs for characters that can be used to render the text.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although fonts are the most common way to change the text, it is necessary to note that there are many many ways to make text look different without changing it&#x27;s font. Some examples are size, weight, kerning, color etc.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a ton of things related to typography including: stroke stem ligature etc. understanding of which is not necessary to make good design. All we need to know is which fonts and what style is necessary for the job at hand.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-basics&quot;&gt;The basics&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use as little as required. This is a general advice while designing anything however this is especially true for typography. Many people go over the board when they discover the plethora of fonts available at their disposition, and they use every font they can find. Which ends up looking quite ugly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Less is more&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;See which fonts go together, try to use a few or even a single font family. You can use styles such as caps, italics, weight, color etc to differentiate the text.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;i.imgur.com&#x2F;LIY4e4p.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In comparison look into the same content with same alignment and positioning as before but the use of only Roboto font family:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;i.imgur.com&#x2F;XZ7rId3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Observe that even though it isn&#x27;t as eye-catching as the previous example, at least the eyes aren&#x27;t catching fire either i.e. it is far more readable to the user. Also note the usage of weight, color and kerning. They provide a guide for the eyes to follow, the main heading is the largest and bold, attracting the eye towards it. The paragraph then follows. The Navbar that cannot be confused with anything else due to its positioning at the top.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Similar things look similar different things look different.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; Buttons should have similar look and fonts, Links should be colored and highlighted similarly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simplicity is not just meant for the style, your content should also apply minimalism. You do not need many complicated words to explain something to the user. You can even use icons to make it more understandable. But do not over do it. Provide text wherever required and use clear language.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Color is a sensitive topic. Some people like this color some that. In typography it isn&#x27;t quite hard to decide what the colors should be. Firstly, any long form content should have a flat color; gradients and effects reduce legibility. Everything else can be based on the color scheme of the project. Say your blog had a red&#x2F;warm color scheme, one example of using the color scheme could be:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;i.imgur.com&#x2F;bGjS8Ca.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;personal-picks&quot;&gt;Personal Picks&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a list of fonts that I really like. They are all free to use for everything.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;inter&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;rsms.me&#x2F;inter&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Inter&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;i.imgur.com&#x2F;8otQbVs.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time I experienced this font I was in love. It is like a modern version of Helevetica with subtle improvements for visibility. This font can be used everywhere from headings to paragraphs to UI and brand text. The versatility and looks make this one of the best overall fonts out there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;manrope&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;sharanda&#x2F;manrope&quot;&gt;Manrope&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;i.imgur.com&#x2F;BrOKvPy.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a pleasing font at all sizes. It is a mix of geometric and neo-grotesque, which gives it an average look. It is a versatile font and can be used in any situation. Various weights mean more flexibility. It sometimes looks awkward with a few specific characters, let us hope it gets better as it is an ongoing project.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;jost&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;indestructibletype.com&#x2F;Jost.html&quot;&gt;Jost*&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;i.imgur.com&#x2F;0sA3qp7.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; geometric free font. It is a modern take on the classic Futura. It&#x27;s shape and proportions have a fresh feel to it. One of my most loved fonts. It makes for a great use anywhere font. With the advent of geometric fonts in modern design, Jost is a nice font to consider for your next design.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;iosevka&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;be5invis&#x2F;Iosevka&quot;&gt;Iosevka&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;i.imgur.com&#x2F;OfyGVbA.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a mechanical and elongated look, Iosevka is beautiful and readable. I use it more that I would like to admit. This is the default monospace font on my system and is used throughout the interface from coding and terminals to everywhere such as status bars. (Customizations on linux are usually referred to ricing. See &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.reddit.com&#x2F;r&#x2F;unixporn&#x2F;top&#x2F;?t=all&quot;&gt;r&#x2F;unixporn&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for examples.) I also use this in my text editor Typora (&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;theme.typora.io&#x2F;theme&#x2F;Xydark&#x2F;&quot;&gt;theme here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;). In fact, the font used to type this article in is none other than Iosevka!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;lato&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.latofonts.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Lato&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;i.imgur.com&#x2F;Nxpnupa.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lato is a humanist sans serif font. It&#x27;s rounded solid nature gives it vibes of summer. It is versatile and looks transparent in body while being distinct in headings. A truly universal typeface with support for several unicode languages, lato deserves the credit for the popularity it has.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;hk-grotesk&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;hanken.co&#x2F;products&#x2F;hk-grotesk&quot;&gt;HK Grotesk&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;i.imgur.com&#x2F;gEWvPV5.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HK Grotesk is a visually attractive and sharp grotesk sans typeface. It brovides a solid and industrial look. All caps looks particularly pleasing. A must use font to spice up the interface.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;playfair-display&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;clauseggers&#x2F;Playfair-Display&quot;&gt;Playfair Display&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;i.imgur.com&#x2F;ZHJWck8.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A stylish and multipurpose heading and banner font. It looks funky and professional at the same time. It is balanced and restrained in a casual fashion. You should be careful not to use it everywhere though.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;roboto&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;fonts.google.com&#x2F;specimen&#x2F;Roboto&quot;&gt;Roboto&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;i.imgur.com&#x2F;WpvykbE.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The classic android font and one of the most used open fonts available. It is Google&#x27;s take on Helevetica, built for the 2.5 billion android devices, it was designed to be incredibly flexible and readable at the same time. A great font to use when you don&#x27;t know what to choose. There are other members of Roboto family that you can also check out: &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;fonts.google.com&#x2F;specimen&#x2F;Roboto+Slab&quot;&gt;Roboto Slab&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;fonts.google.com&#x2F;specimen&#x2F;Roboto+Condensed&quot;&gt;Roboto Condensed&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;fonts.google.com&#x2F;specimen&#x2F;Roboto+Mono&quot;&gt;Roboto Mono&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are various good places to look through to find both inspiration and advice regarding typography, here are the best ones I know:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;material.io&#x2F;design&#x2F;typography&#x2F;understanding-typography.html&quot;&gt;Understanding Typography - Material Design&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.smashingmagazine.com&#x2F;typography-guidelines-and-references&quot;&gt;Typography guidelines and references - Smashing Magazine&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.creativelive.com&#x2F;blog&#x2F;typography-tips&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Typography Tips&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.canva.com&#x2F;learn&#x2F;typography-design&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Typography - Canva&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.reddit.com&#x2F;r&#x2F;typography&quot;&gt;r&#x2F;typography&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dribbble.com&#x2F;shots&#x2F;popular&#x2F;typography&quot;&gt;Typography Shots - Dribbble&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here are some places you can grab fonts for free:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;material.io&#x2F;design&#x2F;typography&#x2F;understanding-typography.html&quot;&gt;Google Fonts&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;open-foundry.com&#x2F;fonts&quot;&gt;Open Foundry&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.websiteplanet.com&#x2F;blog&#x2F;best-free-fonts&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Best free fonts - Website Planet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.dafont.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Dafont&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Warning: Several of these fonts may not be available for commercial projects&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;fontlibrary.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Font Library&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;ryanoasis&#x2F;nerd-fonts&quot;&gt;Nerd Fonts&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;designtheway.com&#x2F;most-used-fonts-alternative-google-fonts&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Alternative Google fonts for premium fonts&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;gist.github.com&#x2F;xypnox&#x2F;b1364330ef326172b2f84a89d08e5e96&quot;&gt;a gist&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of a list of fonts that I prepared a few months back while searching for fonts. It may turn out useful for some font hunters.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are tons of more theory and practice in the field of typography, you can even go ahead and make your own font, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;xypnox&#x2F;Oliver&#x2F;&quot;&gt;like I did&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. But I feel that I have covered the most important aspects of typography here. And the provided links and resources are enough for a head-start.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Type is a beautiful group of letters, not a group of beautiful letters.” - Matthew Carter&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As always, suggestions and additions are welcome.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>3D plot on a Chess Board</title>
		<published>2019-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/chessproblems/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/chessproblems/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;cover-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;&amp;#x2F;blag&amp;#x2F;images&amp;#x2F;chess-problems.png&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;desc&quot;&gt;
    Rendered using Blender
  &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I was interested in this chess puzzle:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;i.imgur.com&#x2F;PyhIvWY.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this very peculiar position we have to place the black king to a square such that &lt;em&gt;it is not in check&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and with white being next to move &lt;em&gt;black gets mated in the maximum number of moves&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. That is white takes most moves to mate black.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve such a problem, we can take help of our friend &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;stockfishchess.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Stockfish&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Using the online chess website &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;lichess.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Lichess&#x27;s&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;lichess.org&#x2F;analysis&#x2F;8&#x2F;8&#x2F;8&#x2F;4k3&#x2F;8&#x2F;8&#x2F;PPPK4&#x2F;RNBQ4_w_-_-_0_1&quot;&gt;analysis&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;lichess.org&#x2F;editor&#x2F;8&#x2F;8&#x2F;8&#x2F;4k3&#x2F;8&#x2F;8&#x2F;PPPK4&#x2F;RNBQ4_w_-_-_0_1&quot;&gt;editor&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; features, we can determine the number of moves to mate for all the available squares.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing such an analysis and collecting the data we get the following chart:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;i.imgur.com&#x2F;IfyWR5U.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which seems quite interesting and promising as we can then deduce that the &lt;em&gt;safest&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; place for the black king is in the &lt;em&gt;upper right center&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; of the board. Moreover, we see that the squares near the pieces and the edge of the board have lower values as they are places where the black king gets checkmated quickly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can then create a 3D representation of this data by giving the squares the height of the numbers in them. Using some &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.blender.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;blender&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; magic we get the following in 3D:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;i.imgur.com&#x2F;TSqTVhE.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which is quite nice to look at. The 4 squares with value of 8 can be seen to dominate and they are surrounded by squares of gradually decreasing height. The transparency gives the feel of volume, and a look on squares hidden from view.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bit more playing at blender&#x27;s materials and shading we can beautify the image further:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;i.imgur.com&#x2F;JYfzd9w.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went ahead and created the white pieces for reference to the problem and we get:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;i.imgur.com&#x2F;MJ1PcsS.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have this final detailed infographic about the entire thing in one image:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;i.imgur.com&#x2F;NMcctiw.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;extras&quot;&gt;Extras&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few changes in the cameras location and focus gives us these few spectacular shots:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;i.imgur.com&#x2F;rKq7G8o.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;i.imgur.com&#x2F;NchTPnB.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now since I have all the pieces created for chess, I setup an entire board with the starting position in blender:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;i.imgur.com&#x2F;fdgn0HT.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking careful look at both the king and the queen, both of them looked out of proportion and awkward. Hence they were modified and we got a new nice setup:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;i.imgur.com&#x2F;iuN0LLY.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there is one more angle for the last render:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;i.imgur.com&#x2F;art6dIt.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the imgur album for all the images: https:&#x2F;&#x2F;imgur.com&#x2F;a&#x2F;kvxUJW6&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Nettigritty Fraud</title>
		<published>2019-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/nettigritty-fraud/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/nettigritty-fraud/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just so everyone knows&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Date&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;: Fri, 8 Nov 2019 18:19:02 +0530&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Subject&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;: I am deeply unsatisfied with your business policy&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;To&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;: support@nettigritty.com&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Cc&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;: mail@hackinout.co&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi Nettigritty,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your company is an awesome company, it has great services and exceptional policies, including the one to give free domains to the Hackathon participants, so that they may utilize it. And if what they make is successful, they will gladly pay the registration fees after the first year. And I am very pleased by this. It promotes people to develop applications and go worldwide without the restriction of buying a domain name. It is a perfect scheme, well, almost perfect.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I registered the domain name, I was expecting that I would get a free domain name for a year, but no. I got it for only two damn weeks. Not because the domain expired, but because the your humanity did. I was expecting you guys to keep information that I share with you private. But no, the marketing head has to make his already expanding ass fatter than the fucking moon. You want to dupe everyone, you want to steal, lie, misdirect and even threaten so that you may earn money.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am writing this email in the hope that it will be read by a human and not the greedy asshole who invented the trick of giving free domains and charging for privacy protection. I am not against you making money, I am against the policy that you suckers have used to make it. How is it even acceptable in this world of privacy that your beloved company makes the details of registration available to everyone, when every single competitor of yours adds this feature as a default.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And please don&#x27;t say that I am inexperienced, I am, but I am also a happy customer of Google Domains, who have been very conveniently keeping my privacy out of the hands of you guys. You know why people these days fear that their private life might become public? Because of you and your company.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I accept that I made a mistake to trust in your company and I deeply apologize for the same. Also, I accept that I should have read the entire terms and conditions before registering the domain.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I request you to please delete the domain name registration from under my name. I do not want that domain name, and if I ever do, I will buy it from any other domain provider. I will also try to inform as many people around me as possible about your fraudulent business policy and the complete disrespect of basic human privacy, and to never ever use any of your services.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;NOTICE:&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;YOUR PREMIUM XYPNOX PRIVACY PROTECTION HAS EXPIRED. TO AVOID FURTHER EMAILS FROM ANGRY CUSTOMERS, PLEASE RENEW YOUR HUMANITY WITHIN 1 WEEK. FORTUNATELY, IT DOESN&#x27;T CHARGE ANYTHING.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS. Hackinout, please do not spread the fraudulent schemes of these people from now on. It would also help a lot if you could mail the other participants about the twist involved in their greedy scheme so that people may remain safe.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regards and curses,
xypnox
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;xypnox.com&quot;&gt;xypnox.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; =&amp;gt; &lt;em&gt;Bought on Google Domains which I will gladly renew this year.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Designing a Poster</title>
		<published>2019-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/designing-a-poster/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/designing-a-poster/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;cover-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;&amp;#x2F;blag&amp;#x2F;images&amp;#x2F;designing-a-poster.png&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;desc&quot;&gt;
    visit posters.xypnox.com to view all posters.
  &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To design a good poster,
you have to design 100 bad posters first.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been making posters for a couple of years. And I have learned a lot, not just about how to make a good poster, but also why most posters are bad. And here I present a minimal guide on how to make nice posters.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should say upfront that I am not a great designer. What you see is a combination of years of bad design and a genuine interest in creating something better than before. If you are interested in viewing some of my posters, you can visit &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;posters.xypnox.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;posters.xypnox.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A while ago a junior from &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;kossiitkgp.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;KOSS&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; asked me the following:&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hey xypnox,&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;I am very interested in designing beautiful things like the new design you made for koss Can u please guide how should I start?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And I replied:&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I apologize for the very late response.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I currently use Inkscape to create the posters and designs that I have made for KOSS. It is a free and Open Source tool so you can easily use it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing about design is not about creating but observing. I have spent far more time looking at and appreciating good design throughout all the mediums, be it physical like posters, book covers, product wrappers, devices, cars, etc to digital like websites, apps, videos, music cover-arts, etc. The places that you can take inspiration from are endless. You will slowly develop a sense of what looks beautiful and what doesn&#x27;t.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can list you a few rules but they wouldn&#x27;t capture everything and will only be recommendations and they can still be broken. The point is that you should start observing and create &lt;em&gt;designs&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; just for the sake of creating them. I used to do this a lot. I would create things that I didn&#x27;t share anywhere, I just made them to practice and in several instances, test whether I could make something similar to what I had in my mind.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A blog that I used to read just for fun was: &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.smashingmagazine.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.smashingmagazine.com&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still recommend it but it has a lot of content and you don&#x27;t need to go through everything.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cycle that I would recommend you to follow is Observe -&amp;gt; Learn -&amp;gt; Experiment&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got to know of graphic design &amp;quot;forums&amp;quot; pretty late. As late as the previous year to be exact. A few of them are:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Behance &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.behance.net&#x2F;&quot;&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.behance.net&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dribble &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dribbble.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dribbble.com&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4chan GD &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;boards.4channel.org&#x2F;gd&#x2F;&quot;&gt;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;boards.4channel.org&#x2F;gd&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reddit &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.reddit.com&#x2F;r&#x2F;Design&#x2F;&quot;&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.reddit.com&#x2F;r&#x2F;Design&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would recommend taking inspiration from these. Specifically, observe what people comment and discuss in the Reddit and 4chan forums.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, for web design, I use to go at:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.awwwards.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.awwwards.com&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;material.io&#x2F;design&#x2F;&quot;&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;material.io&#x2F;design&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;developer.apple.com&#x2F;design&#x2F;&quot;&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;developer.apple.com&#x2F;design&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope you have a great time designing awesome stuff. I would love if you could post any drafts in #design channel in slack so we can critique it for improvements.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote a blog post about design a long time ago about a few things that I thought were important: &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;design-tips&#x2F;&quot;&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;design-tips&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &lt;code&gt;Please don&#x27;t open this - not in the original message&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regards,
xypnox&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a while back. And if you don&#x27;t want to read everything then the message is enough. But if you have not satisfied your hunger, carry on!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;to-develop-a-sense-of-design&quot;&gt;To Develop a &lt;em&gt;sense&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; of Design&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;observe-good-design&quot;&gt;Observe Good Design&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start observing good design.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you start to appreciate good design, you should be able to recognize bad design and the ways to correct it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We frequently and easily criticize bad design. That a poster is ugly. That an icon is of poor quality. That a website is imperfect. But when it comes to fixing the bad design, we are left clueless. Even a four-year-old can tell you that something doesn&#x27;t look good. But what exactly doesn&#x27;t look good is another question entirely. It is a good exercise to not only find that a design is faulty but also find the faults in it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;practice-practice-practice&quot;&gt;Practice, Practice, Practice&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no better substitute for learning to make a poster than actually making a poster. You should experiment with making a poster when you don&#x27;t have to make a poster. Try different styles, try replicating an idea you saw earlier, try experimenting with color, typography, alignment. You are free to practice with your heart&#x27;s content.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is there to lose in experimenting? Nothing. Everything is freely available. You can grab stock images from &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;unsplash.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, Try colors from &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;color.adobe.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Adobe Colors&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, Fonts from &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;fonts.google.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Google fonts&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Nothing is stopping you from designing good posters other than you yourself. In fact, all the recent posters I have designed were created from free stuff using free software such as &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.figma.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Figma&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;inkscape.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Inkscape&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;making-a-poster&quot;&gt;Making a Poster&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step of the design process is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; to open your favorite software and start making a nice poster. The principle step involves thought. You have to start thinking - What you are making? Who are you making it for? What is the main concern? Is this the only way to do it? - These questions help you justify the poster and the decisions you shall make while designing it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;who-are-your-final-consumers&quot;&gt;Who are your final consumers?&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who will be finally looking at your design? - Your target audience decides most of the boundaries that you can explore.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After determining your audience&#x27;s demographics, decide what they want, what they like, what they are interested in and what will make them happy. Answering these questions will go a far way in relieving you from minor headaches such as Which fonts to use, What should be the alignment, Is a modern style good or the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.interaction-design.org&#x2F;literature&#x2F;topics&#x2F;skeuomorphism&quot;&gt;Skeuomorphic&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; real-life style better?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, it is also important to remember that you are designing for yourself first. Every poster you make should look good to you. If it doesn&#x27;t, then it is not your best design. And if it does look good, chances are it will look good to others too.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-the-main-problem&quot;&gt;What is the main problem?&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a main problem that every design intends to solve. With most posters, it is grabbing the attention of the audience and encouraging them to read the complete poster.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence, you want your poster to be as catchy as possible. It should be able to stop someone from scrolling over to actually read what is written on the poster. To make a poster catchy, it is not necessary to make it visually perfect. However, the reader is more likely to read a &amp;quot;legible&amp;quot; poster than a &amp;quot;flashy&amp;quot; one.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#x27;t make the poster too :fire: &lt;em&gt;FLASHY&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; :star:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-should-be-the-main-theme-of-the-poster&quot;&gt;What should be the main theme of the poster?&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main theme of the poster sets the stage for everything afterward. The main theme decides which colors to use which fonts would work and what the borders and backgrounds should look like. By theme, I refer to the abstract idea or feeling conveyed through the poster. Such as strong solid lines and bordered and clean text are suitable for an official and formal theme.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your main theme should cater to the audience and should look to solve the main challenge. After you choose the theme, the next steps are building upon the idea and making it into a poster.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;learn-the-tools-or-perhaps-don-t&quot;&gt;Learn the tools, or perhaps don&#x27;t&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a weird notion that people have to learn every nook and cranny of Photoshop before making a poster. I don&#x27;t use Photoshop. And I don&#x27;t get why people are so devoted to it. You don&#x27;t have to know Photoshop or even use Photoshop to create great posters.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best tools are useless in the hands of an idiot.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that doesn&#x27;t mean you have to abandon Photoshop altogether. What I mean is that Photoshop is too &amp;quot;good&amp;quot; for what we are trying to do. It has a thousand features that we may never use, It has a multitude of ways of doing something basic - confusing users of which is the right way. You can stick with Photoshop if you want but I would suggest trying Inkscape and Figma as well. Both are excellent vector graphics editors and guess what they are absolutely free.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, You don&#x27;t need to know everything to start designing. You should have a basic knowledge of how to create shapes, add text, change the font, add images, use layers and gradients, etc. But nothing too fancy is necessary. The reason is that you shall learn the rest by experimenting and creating posters. Whenever you want to do something in your editor, and you don&#x27;t know how to do it, just google how to do it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will never find a video or a tutorial teaching you to make beautiful things that will instantly make you better. You can learn how to use a tool and yet you won&#x27;t be able to design anything awesome just by the knowledge of using the tool. It is like the difference in learning to write and writing a magnum opus. You can only acquire it with time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;typography&quot;&gt;Typography&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most under-appreciated part of designing posters: &lt;strong&gt;Typography&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Even though it is boring, it is just plain text, it is just some words, you can always find ways to spice things up, you can always make the content the best part of your design!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is very close to the core of minimalism, where the focus is on content rather than the ability of content to look good.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic guidelines for working with text are:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People read the thing that attracts their attention first.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People read from left to right.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People expect the important details to be highlighted.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People expect things related to each other to be with each other.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these simple principles, we can get a good idea of what our text should be and how we can format it. The &lt;strong&gt;Title&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; should be the primary focus grabber and should ideally be the first thing the eyes land on. Whatever the user needs to read or interact with should be prominently visible and legible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another facet of text is the font. Font is the dress text wears. When your poster is formal, fonts that look professional are recommended. Open Sans, Lato, Crimson, etc are a great choice for a formal setting. And in design, what looks good on a formal design usually, with little modifications also looks good with informal scenarios as well. So the fonts noted above are overall a great choice for several themes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to step into the informal territory you can use a combination of display and handwriting fonts. But, remember to make sure that the text is legible. Nice fonts are nothing if the viewer can&#x27;t read what is written. It is a good choice to use sans-serif fonts for the smaller sized texts as they are the most readable at a smaller scale.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;digesting-criticism&quot;&gt;Digesting Criticism&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you cannot tolerate criticism then, unfortunately, designing is not for you. You will always get an unhealthy dose of criticism for everything that you design. And for beginners, it could be downright un-motivational. Ignore every comment that does not contain suggestions. And those that do, take them with a grain of salt. See if the suggestions actually improve the design. And remember that the final decision to include any change in the poster should rest on you and thus you should choose wisely.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;don-t-do-this&quot;&gt;Don&#x27;t Do this&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can do the things listed below if you are perfectly sure you are not intoxicated, and you understand that actions have consequences.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&#x27;t stick stuff to the very edge.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&#x27;t use more than 3 colors. (shades and tints are fine)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&#x27;t use more than 3 fonts.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&#x27;t use every effect on a single object, like gradient, 3D, Shadow, Glow and Outline on a single piece of text.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&#x27;t Align everything differently.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And there is unique &lt;strong&gt;Don&#x27;t Do This&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; point that needs thorough discussion:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;don-t-use-templates&quot;&gt;Don&#x27;t use templates&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I understand that sometimes you are bored, with only a few minutes left and everyone expects a poster from you. Then, it may be plausible that you take a template from the wen and change the texts and send over the nice poster that you have &amp;quot;designed&amp;quot;. This is no design.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never get yourself in a position like this. You will never create anything of value while you are limited in time. Start early. And with time, perhaps you may develop a knack of designing posters quickly. But till then., begin at least 48 hours before the release of the poster.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, coming back to the main point. DO NOT USE THE DAMN TEMPLATES. Because you learn nothing. Do you think you may have learned a great deal by creating posters using templates? What have you actually learned? Using the font tool to change the text. That&#x27;s it. And I can guarantee I can make a better poster than a template-driven &lt;em&gt;designer&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; in frigging Microsoft Paint.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Templates are a great solution for people who don&#x27;t have time, not for people who claim to be a member of a design team.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Templates are there to teach you how a poster should look like. They are there for inspiration and imitation. Take ideas from the templates and design a poster yourself. Make the squares and circles and all shapes yourself. You can definitely use icons and imagery etc. You don&#x27;t have to photograph every picture you use in your poster yourself.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With time you shall learn to design. And with luck and practice, you can become best.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have some suggestions, please comment below or feel free to reach me!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Apps that I Love</title>
		<published>2019-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/apps-that-i-love/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/apps-that-i-love/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;cover-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;&amp;#x2F;blag&amp;#x2F;images&amp;#x2F;apps-i-love-cover.jpg&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;desc&quot;&gt;
    Photo by Amith Nair on Unsplash
  &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;long the several years, I have been using computers and smartphones, I have discovered a few real gems that have adorned my gadgets. I present here a list of Applications, for desktop and mobile that I have loved using and would recommend to anyone within a heartbeat.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe you may already know some of them but perhaps the reasons why I like them would differ from yours, so read on!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;vs-code&quot;&gt;VS Code&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blag&#x2F;images&#x2F;apps-i-love&#x2F;vscode.png&quot; alt=&quot;My VSCode setup&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started proper coding with &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.sublimetext.com&#x2F;3&quot;&gt;Sublime Text 3 beta&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I loved that text editor. It was smooth and beautiful. Then came &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;atom.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Atom&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, another marvel and a beast of another world. A slow behemoth that could do almost anything through extensions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And recently I was introduced to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;code.visualstudio.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;VS Code&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I accept that I did not try it due to Microsoft&#x27;s badge on it, at first. However, once I started using it I couldn&#x27;t stop. It was both fast, extensible and more importantly, it got work done. You didn&#x27;t have to spend hours finding the right extensions and then setting them up. It came with all the essentials included and had great official support for a lot of the languages that I used. The git integration is also awesome and especially helpful for large projects.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For anyone that still uses Atom or Sublime Text, switch to VS Code. Just try it and you might never go back.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;telegram&quot;&gt;Telegram&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blag&#x2F;images&#x2F;apps-i-love&#x2F;telegram.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the days of the boom of messaging apps, I tried a lot of them. I tried WhatsApp, Viber, Line, Wechat, Messenger, Hangouts and then I settled on &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;telegram.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Telegram&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. There are a few reasons why. Telegram is faster than most of them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is also secure and has a track record of not sharing data with any government agency or third party. And it has stickers and gifs that are very intuitive and easy to use. Half of my messages on my family&#x27;s telegram group are using Stickers and GIFs. I recommend it almost everyone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;ubuntu-i3wm&quot;&gt;Ubuntu + i3wm&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blag&#x2F;images&#x2F;apps-i-love&#x2F;i3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been a strong proponent of everything Linux, and I will not go on and repeat why I like &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.ubuntu.com&#x2F;download&#x2F;desktop&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and any Linux distro in general. However, I will present to you a different way of using your laptop: using a tiling window manager. A &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;wiki.archlinux.org&#x2F;index.php&#x2F;window_manager&quot;&gt;window manager&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a very lightweight application that controls how each window looks and behaves on your desktop.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i3 is a beginner friendly and fast window manager. I would recommend you to start with &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;Airblader&#x2F;i3&quot;&gt;i3-gaps&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (for those cool gaps between windows).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to being lightweight, It is fast and uses the screen-space efficiently. Not only is a WM fast in itself, but most WMs also use keybindings so changing windows and virtual desktops (Not VMs mind you) is a breeze. I have thoroughly enjoyed my experience with i3 and I would recommend anyone willing to give a little time to learn how to use it as it is very different from how you regularly use your OS. Here is a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=j1I63wGcvU4&quot;&gt;brief tutorial&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; about i3 which helped me get started.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;typora&quot;&gt;Typora&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blag&#x2F;images&#x2F;apps-i-love&#x2F;typora.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;typora.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Typora&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a minimal markdown editor. But as Mr. Nicholas Burroughs aptly said:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Minimalism is not a lack of something. It’s simply the perfect amount of something.&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typora is just the right amount of markdown editor you need. It behaves similar to a WYSIWYG editor but hides its features behind a set of keybindings and views. It is simple to use if you are familiar with markdown and very very enjoyable for distraction-free writing. In fact, I have written this post on Typora itself and I have even created &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;theme.typora.io&#x2F;theme&#x2F;Xydark&#x2F;&quot;&gt;a theme&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;alto-s-adventure&quot;&gt;Alto&#x27;s Adventure&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blag&#x2F;images&#x2F;apps-i-love&#x2F;alto.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#x27;s throw in a game for some fun. &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;altosadventure.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Alto&#x27;s Adventure&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is &lt;strong&gt;the&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; game that I play. I don&#x27;t have any other games on my phone and even though I don&#x27;t play it often nowadays, this is my favorite game so far on Android. It is an infinite runner where you can jump and do backflips. But don&#x27;t let the simplicity distract you. With a marvelous soundtrack and a phenomenal procedurally generated environment, It will surely make your evenings a hell lot of fun. Also, don&#x27;t forget to try Zen Mode.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;joey-for-reddit&quot;&gt;Joey for Reddit&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blag&#x2F;images&#x2F;apps-i-love&#x2F;joey.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another Android Reddit app. But &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;play.google.com&#x2F;store&#x2F;apps&#x2F;details?id=o.o.joey&amp;amp;hl=en_IN&quot;&gt;Joey&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has the highest ratings on the play store (4.9 &#x2F; 5). And there are plenty of reasons why; highly customizable, fast, gesture-based, fullscreen immersive content. It is a fun app and makes the Reddit experience on mobile fantastic. If you are a Redditor you should definitely check this App.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;figma&quot;&gt;Figma&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blag&#x2F;images&#x2F;apps-i-love&#x2F;figma.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.figma.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Figma&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a design tool. It is a fast prototyping software and is available as an online app. It is very easy and intuitive and has great videos on getting started. It is free for all the basic usage and I have had a great time using it. I have recently started designing a lot more on figma and my previous pick was Inkscape, which wasn&#x27;t so nice as it had a few performance issues and it was a vector drawing application, not exactly a design app.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;eboox-ebook-reader&quot;&gt;Eboox Ebook reader&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blag&#x2F;images&#x2F;apps-i-love&#x2F;eboox.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another Android app, it is an eBook Reader and that&#x27;s it. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;play.google.com&#x2F;store&#x2F;apps&#x2F;details?id=com.reader.books&amp;amp;hl=en_IN&quot;&gt;Eboox&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has very basic book management but where it excels is the reading experience. It is simply exceptional, with the included &amp;quot;Tinos&amp;quot; font, it is a great and minimal Ebook reader for mobile. You can highlight quotes and put bookmarks too. But the reason I like this app is that it does one thing and it does it very well.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;youtube-vanced&quot;&gt;Youtube Vanced&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blag&#x2F;images&#x2F;apps-i-love&#x2F;YouTube-Vanced.webp&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know you are smart and you have an adblocker installed on your browser. But what about mobile? You can&#x27;t prevent ads from showing up on Youtube on mobile, but can you? &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xda-developers.com&#x2F;youtube-vanced-apk&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Youtube vanced&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a perfect replacement for youtube albeit with a few minor tweaks, a true black dark mode, ability to play higher resolution videos than supported, the ability for background playback (you can let the app play the video as a music player in your notifications!) but most importantly no adds.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As most of you might have guessed by now, no it is not available on Play Store and for obvious reasons. Hence, you have to side-load it and do a minor setup if you want to login using your Google account. However, I think it is worth the effort and is simply fantastic.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun fact &lt;code&gt;Youtube Vanced = Youtube Advanced - Ad&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That might be all that I have, for now, If I get to experience anything else, I will make sure to share it in another blog post!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>One of the Dark Days</title>
		<published>2019-04-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-04-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/one-of-the-dark-days/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/one-of-the-dark-days/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I fall too soon and too deep&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Into waters I am unaware of.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
And I forget to swim&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
When I need to.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
I inhale the water&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Knowing all well,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
that it isn&#x27;t well.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
And then I cry,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Try to find faults&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
In others when I am wrong,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
And in myself when others have wronged.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
I find myself&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
At crossroads&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Where every road is a bad omen.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
And yet, I have to choose one&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
And I go on blindly&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Trusting&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
That it will all be alright&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
When nothing actually is&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Alright.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
I am as broken&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
As I am perfect,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Perfect imperfections.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
The more I know&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
The less I understand.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
It feels like I am climbing&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Falling stairs.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
I try to find the key&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Key to success&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Key to happiness&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Key to satisfaction&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
That I have lost&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Long ago, beyond recovery&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
I try to have hope&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
That I will find it&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Because&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Hope is all I have, and&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
I don&#x27;t want to be locked in.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
I try too much&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
And do too little.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Written on one of the dark days.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Two Pens</title>
		<published>2019-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/two-pens/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/two-pens/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;cover-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;&amp;#x2F;blag&amp;#x2F;images&amp;#x2F;two-pens.jpg&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;desc&quot;&gt;
    Photo by pulkit jain on Unsplash (Modified)
  &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a busy school,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
two friends sat together&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
in mutual distrust.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Each buying the same&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
luxury pen last weekend&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
and that hurt&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
their swag level.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first of the two&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
used the pen far and few&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
the second didn&#x27;t.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
He abused the pen&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
to scratches and scuffs&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
having no care at all,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
for him, it was&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
just another pen.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Days passed, Weeks passed.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
The first&#x27;s pen shinned,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
where the seconds dulled.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Jealousy rose again&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
in second&#x27;s heart.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
He was silent and discrete&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
and switched his pen&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
with the first&#x27;s!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first discovered however&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
the second&#x27;s crime.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
He ran to the teacher&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
with teenage whine.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
The teacher was already tired&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Said that the pens were the same&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
and punished the first&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
for being so lame.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first swallowed the &lt;em&gt;truth&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
and took the pen that&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
the second misused.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
He dumped the pen&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
with scratches and scruffs&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
into the dustbin&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
even if it worked just fine&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&amp;quot;Because it wasn&#x27;t mine&amp;quot;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day, the first returned&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Blood filled with anger&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
and eyes with revenge.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
He took the pen&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
that the second stole&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
and twine in half&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
the beauty parted in two.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He stood there&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
with the pen he cared for&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
for days, for weeks&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
broken in his hands&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
and eyes wet with tears.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
For love is strong&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
but weak in the face of hate.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, I thought of writing what I understood from the poem. However I would rather appreciate the reader to provide feedback on what you understand of the poem!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Moving Notes to Github</title>
		<published>2019-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/moving-notes-to-github/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/moving-notes-to-github/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;cover-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;&amp;#x2F;blag&amp;#x2F;images&amp;#x2F;notes.jpg&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;desc&quot;&gt;
    Photo by Brannon Naito on Unsplash
  &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never had a unified place to store notes earlier. I usually just remembered important things and wrote down the other things anywhere I liked. But after a year in college I could not keep on remembering everything. I should make it clear early on that I do not take extensive notes. I only jot down things that I find important like thoughts, quotes, project ideas, some literature etc. I had always looked for a simple note taking solution. My ideal note taking solution required the following:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Easy and quick to store notes (The longer it takes to note something down the less motivated I am to note it down)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should be backed up (Its important! you don&#x27;t want to loose that groundbreaking idea in a device failure)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Service Independent&#x2F;Personal (I don&#x27;t trust them, I will be limited by what the service has to offer)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flexibility (I should be able to store everything and anything and organize it to my liking)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supports multiple devices (Using a single device for note taking is just plain stupid)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;backstory&quot;&gt;Backstory&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a backstory covering ll the apps I used before turning to Github. Feel free to skip this section.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I have tried to find an ideal service with the above features for a long long time. I used to use &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;evernote.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Evernote&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; a long time ago. In fact It might have been my first note taking app. But that was before I switched to Linux. In linux the scenario becomes a lot tougher. The services available always seem to lack something or another. Either they do not sync, are limited only to linux, or are proprietary. A service that I really liked was &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;simplenote.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Simple Note&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It was a very minimal note taking app from the creators of wordpress and had seamless sync between devices. I actually used it to store notes for some time rather than just testing it and hating and moving on.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But like every thing in this world, it was imperfect. It was very limited in the type of notes it could store, the management of notes was very primitive. And, simple note didn&#x27;t use great encryption. At that time, I didn&#x27;t need a note taking service desperately and hence I slowly stopped using Simple Note. Simple note&#x27;s desktop client was based on electron.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later on, with the improvements in electron, several note taking apps emerged in the wild. I really loved the ideas behind them, Markdown support, minimal design, live rendering to get a WYSIWYG like feel. But the catch was that there was no organization or sync. You just edited a markdown file and saved it to your device. I then started using my text editor (Atom at that time) as my note editor just because one electron was already too much for an old PC. I saved them in the documents folder. No sync no search nothing. (I did not know linux search from command-line because I was used GUI most of the time)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few note apps designed specifically for programmers like &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;laverna.cc&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Larvena&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, Never got it running, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;abricotine.brrd.fr&#x2F;&quot;&gt;arbicotine&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, Really liked this one, plus it was open source but developers responded slowly to issues, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;boostnote.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Boostnote&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, A very full featured note taking application which was simply overwhelming to my tiny brain, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.tagspaces.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Tag Sapces&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, What the hell was this? tags for all your files, like seriously? All these applications felt like using a chainsaw to open a can of coke. They aimed to be too ambitious but lacked the basics.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Android landscape, things weren&#x27;t any better. The thing with cross-platform applications is that most often you end up with an awesome application on one platform and a barely usable one on others. Very few applications are actually good on all the platforms that they support. Back then, I used to download and install gazillions of applications and I can say that I have tried my fair share of note applications for android. I didn&#x27;t use Evernote on android because I started using android a long time after I left Evernote for desktop.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did encounter a few great applications for android though. The first one was &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;play.google.com&#x2F;store&#x2F;apps&#x2F;details?id=com.underwood.monospace&quot;&gt;Monospace&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It was a minimal markdown note editor. It did a things beautifully, It was unobtrusive and used tags for organization. However It did not have any sync and since I used mobile as a secondary device, it was a deal breaker. I also used apps similar to Monospace, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;play.google.com&#x2F;store&#x2F;apps&#x2F;details?id=com.jotterpad.x&quot;&gt;JotterPad&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;play.google.com&#x2F;store&#x2F;apps&#x2F;details?id=co.easy4u.writer&quot;&gt;Writer+&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; etc But they were worse than Monospace and I left them in few hours of usage.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a note editing app stood as a great example of design, It would be &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;play.google.com&#x2F;store&#x2F;apps&#x2F;details?id=com.dinosaur.cwfei.materialnotes&quot;&gt;Material Notes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It was such a beauty to use. The notes were colored and the usage of monospace font was just icing on the cake. But this app didn&#x27;t do anything else. I used it only to store word meanings while I read the works of Robin Hobb. It was a beautiful app but not a great option for general note taking.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An app that was almost perfect was &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;play.google.com&#x2F;store&#x2F;apps&#x2F;details?id=com.zoho.notebook&quot;&gt;Notebook&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by Zoho. It was a great experience to use. Notes were arranged into notebooks, several media attachments could be made, and the editing, though not markdown, was quite good. It offered sync to servers of Zoho and also had a desktop web version. However, It just felt a little off. The app seemed that it was a bet project which lacked polish and the web version was just OK, the web-clipper was terrible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also used &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;play.google.com&#x2F;store&#x2F;apps&#x2F;details?id=net.ia.iawriter&quot;&gt;iAWriter&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The greatest plus was the ability to sync to Google drive. But since Google drive does not have a sync app for Linux and the web version of Drive displays markdown as a bunch of unprocessed text just irritates the hell out of me. I do like the swipe navigation, minimal look, night mode with absolute blacks and export options of iAWriter. But a weird bug related to switching to different application makes you loose the note that you just typed for last half hour just made me feel helpless. The same happened when you switched different device orientations. With such a critical flaw, I simply decided to move on.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I moved on again. And I finally have setup a workflow for storing notes that I can see myself use in the near future. Although, like always, I will switch to the next hot thing :wink:.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-setup&quot;&gt;The setup&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;typora.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Typora&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to write notes on Laptop. It is a brilliant markdown editor and one of the primary reasons I prefer the current setup. Typora is built on electron but since I do not use an ancient PC anymore, I do not need to worry about electron apps taking too much RAM on my laptop. Typora is currently in beta and is available for free. Similar text editors exist and you can use those as well. But having tried a few, I find typora very polished and reliable. I use it even to write my blog posts. In fact, this very blog post was written on Typora.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has all the basics right. A minimal interface, themeable, relatively fast, different edit modes, syntax highlighting for code bocks, emojis, math support with latex syntax, shortcuts for markdown syntaxs, and inline display of image urls. What more can you ask for from a text editor? Git integration maybe :thinking:. And I even made a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;theme.typora.io&#x2F;theme&#x2F;Xydark&#x2F;&quot;&gt;theme for Typora&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to match my system.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Android side, I have gone completely sadistic. I use Keep to store the quick thoughts that I come across and since keep is very usable and quick, I do not need a completely overpowered app for android.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;sync&quot;&gt;Sync&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;But they are two completely different applications, How do you sync them?&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simple answer, Manually. I do not need to write down everything I usually just put small hints and important points on Keep and then copy them over to my desktop editor by using Keep&#x27;s fairly decent web interface. Then I finally edit and store the &lt;em&gt;good version&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; if the note. It is a hard thing, and I do not have my notes as editable on mobile but it is an acceptable compromise to make, At least for me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now comes the real magic. Sync from desktop to Github. Unless you have been living under a rock you may know that Github recently announced free unlimited repos with at most three collaborators. This means that although you can&#x27;t move your exponentially increasing startup to GitHub for free, you can move personal stuff If you weren&#x27;t a student developer already. With the announcement of free private repos, you can reliably store your data on github just like all your code and GitHub is good enough to provide a decent web experience while reading markdown files.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the hard part is to sync the local repo. If you have ever used git, you would know that to actually save your work, You have to &lt;em&gt;Save the file&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;em&gt;Add it to staging&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;em&gt;Write a decent Commit message&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;em&gt;Push it to github&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;em&gt;Provide password if using HTTP&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. This whole chore is enough to drive anyone crazy. But there are ways to avoid this. And here I present my solution:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use a bash script to automatically check for any changes to files, then add them to staging, commit them using a somewhat descriptive message, then pull any changes on github, finally push to github. I have also configured cache credential store for git that saves the github login passwords so that I do not have to enter it manually. Then finally, I have added a cronjob for every 15 minutes to run the sync script so It updates my notes to github automagically.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the bash script:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;bash&quot; class=&quot;language-bash &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;#!&amp;#x2F;bin&amp;#x2F;bash

gstatus=`git status --porcelain`

if [ ${#gstatus} -ne 0 ]
then

    git add --all
    git commit -m &amp;quot;$gstatus&amp;quot;

	git pull
    git push

fi
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The beauty of this script is the &lt;code&gt;git status --porcelain&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; command. It outputs a concise message about all the files that were modified. It can be used for both checking that if there was any change in the folder and also as a commit message.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the sync setup, I had to copy all the notes from previous services cause why not. It was just a matter of copy and paste. I am now left to my imagination to fill the repo with future notes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Happy Note taking&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The Elderling Realm</title>
		<published>2018-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/the-elderling-realm/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/the-elderling-realm/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;cover-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;&amp;#x2F;blag&amp;#x2F;images&amp;#x2F;the-elderling-realm.jpg&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;desc&quot;&gt;
    Photo by Michael LaRosa on Unsplash
  &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The elderling realm is not a single book. It is not even a series of books, it is a universe in which several series written by the author Robin Hobb take place. I completed three series out of five main series released till now. And I have thoroughly enjoyed her work. The books are very easy to recommend and are considered classics among recent fantasy novels. I will try to keep this review as free from spoilers as I can.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world of the elderling represents a medieval society mixed with dragons, pirates and the slight touch of magic. The stories or I should say epics begin smoothly and are carried forward effortlessly. It never feels like the author was trying to make a point or desperately moving the story forward in a single direction. It feels as if you are watching a natural progression of events. The smooth and tranquil writing style of Robin Hobb is the best part amongst a stellar set of novels.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first series, The Farseer Trilogy, depicts the life of Fitz Chivalry Farseer from boyhood to young adult. The story is narrated in first person, and at several intervals you will find yourself nodding at the judgement of the protagonist. You will find very slight magic throughout the story, completely different from the bespoken Harry Potter novels which have magic as their central theme. You will relate to every character in the novels and find them similar to people you meet everyday. Take note that actions in one series affect the others as well.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second series, The Livship Traders Trilogy, follows the story of the Bingtown traders, the pirate isles, the Rain wild traders and the state of Jamalia. It is narrated in third person and frequently switches between several protagonists. The number of characters developed in this series is staggering. You may even feel overwhelmed while reading the first few books, since at first the stories feel disjointed. But they come together beautifully in the end and it contains some of the most &lt;em&gt;cry able&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; moments in any novel that I have ever read. Lookout for the words of Sa while reading this series, not because they impact the story but because they are filled with wisdom.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you missed Fitz in the second series, you will love the third series, The tawny man trilogy. This follows Fitz and the farseer reign after the aftermath of the Red ships war from the first series. This series finds Fitz contemplating his decisions of the old. The series is filled with introspection and high tension. The events in this series tie together events of the previous two series and present a mesmerizing epic. The relationship between the fool and the Fitz presents yet another endearing examples of Friendship.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The works of Robbin Hobb have a general slow theme. The events happen slowly and the environments are immersive. The author takes ample time to develop the characters. The environments are vivid, and the author takes great time to make you hear the sounds, smell the smells and taste the tastes of everything noteworthy. You will have a true experience of living the Castle life, from the life of guards to the that of the Kings and more importantly Assassins.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree that these books are lengthy and consume a lot of time to read. But for someone looking for months of endearing fantasy, these are an easy recommendation. If you ever find yourself to be trapped by the never ending narrative, just finish the book, you will find yourself immersed in the next book before you know.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This series is an open recommendation to everyone who loves to read.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will leave you with a quote that I love:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He shook his head pityingly. “This, more than anything else, is what I have never understood about your people. You can roll dice, and understand that the whole game may hinge on one turn of a die. You deal out cards, and say that all a man&#x27;s fortune for the night may turn upon one hand. But a man&#x27;s whole life, you sniff at, and say, what, this naught of a human, this fisherman, this carpenter, this thief, this cook, why, what can they do in the great wide world? And so you putter and sputter your lives away, like candles burning in a draft.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Not all men are destined for greatness,” I reminded him.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Are you sure, Fitz? Are you sure? What good is a life lived as if it made no difference at all to the great life of the world? A sadder thing I cannot imagine. Why should not a mother say to herself, if I raise this child aright, if I love and care for her, she shall live a life that brings joy to those about her, and thus I have changed the world? Why should not the farmer that plants a seed say to his neighbor, this seed I plant today will feed someone, and that is how I change the world today?”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is philosophy, Fool. I have never had time to study such things.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“No, Fitz, this is life. And no one has time not to think of such things. Each creature in the world should consider this thing, every moment of the heart&#x27;s beating. Otherwise, what is the point of arising each day?”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;― Robin Hobb, Royal Assassin&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>TodX : The Todo Manager</title>
		<published>2018-11-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-11-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/todx-the-todo-manager/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/todx-the-todo-manager/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;cover-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;www.optipess.com&amp;#x2F;comics&amp;#x2F;2018-09-28-927_To-Do_SQ.png&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;desc&quot;&gt;
    Credit - optipess.com
  &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I have been working this past few weeks on a todo application using commandline interface in Python. You can skip the boring backstory and jump right into installation if you want to.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project&#x27;s source code is available at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;xypnox&#x2F;todxpy&#x2F;&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;backstory&quot;&gt;Backstory&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently switched to i3 windows manager just to try it out. And I loved it. I have now become used to living in the terminal. Most of the work except web browsing can be done through the terminal in an efficient way. But i3 is a topic for another post.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was using TickTick for managing my todos till this point. Since TickTick doesn&#x27;t have a native linux interface, it was a pain to use on the desktop. Sure it had extensions for both chrome and firefox and had great sync capabilities but if you wanted to use it you had to open a whole browser and use the mouse to open the TickTick extension. It took a lot of time just to add a todo, which &lt;em&gt;should&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; be a very easy task in and of itself.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence I started looking for a commandline todo app that could sync to Android. It should be simple and fast, thats it, and guess what I couldn&#x27;t find one single app that could do it. Most apps didn&#x27;t even have a native linux app let alone cli. Those fast cli apps were mostly single bash or python scripts and could not sync at all. The GUI todo apps for linux were essentially like text editors huge and clunky.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence I set forth to make one of my own which centered on speed, ease of use, sync capability and customizability. And it should obviously be crossplatform.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sync doesn&#x27;t work yet&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;installation&quot;&gt;Installation&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Command enetered in terminal have a &lt;code&gt;$&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; before them. The output of the terminal doesn&#x27;t have the &lt;code&gt;$&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can install todx using pip:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are using Ubuntu or a Ubuntu based distro:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;bash&quot; class=&quot;language-bash &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;$ pip3 install todx
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;otherwise:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;bash&quot; class=&quot;language-bash &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;$ pip install todx
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default Ubuntu&#x27;s pip is for python2 and hence we need pip3 to install the todx for python3&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To check if it installed correctly run the command:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;bash&quot; class=&quot;language-bash &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;$ todx --version
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should return something like &lt;code&gt;TodX v0.1.2&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. If it shows any error message file an Issue in the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;xypnox&#x2F;todxpy&#x2F;issues&quot;&gt;github repo&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;usage&quot;&gt;Usage&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can view your todos using the simple command:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;bash&quot; class=&quot;language-bash &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;$ todx
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have just installed todx, you wont get any output.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To add a new todo run:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;bash&quot; class=&quot;language-bash &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;$ todx add Make a great website
Added todo:  ☐  Make a great website
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will add a new todo &amp;quot;Make a great website&amp;quot;. You can run &lt;code&gt;todx&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; again to see that the new todo has been added. The empty box &lt;code&gt;☐&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; is not a missing unicode charecter, it is a checkbox and it indicates that the todo has not been marked yet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To mark a todo run:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;bash&quot; class=&quot;language-bash &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;$ todx mark
0 ☐  Make a great website

Which todo you want to mark: 0
What is your new status: v
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This command lists the todos with indexes and asks which todo to mark. Here we choose the &lt;code&gt;0&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; and then the command asks what the status you want to be.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we have chosen &lt;code&gt;v&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; since it closely resembles the tick. When todx displays the todos it changes the &lt;code&gt;v&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; to a &lt;code&gt;☑&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. Neat. But what if you prefer &lt;code&gt;☒&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;? Just use &lt;code&gt;x&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;v&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. To unmark a todo just use a space in the status.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now if you run &lt;code&gt;todx&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; you will see that once you marked your todo you can&#x27;t see it. This is because by default &lt;code&gt;todx&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; only shows unmarked, in other words, not done todos. If you want to view all the todos, marked and unmarked you can run:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;bash&quot; class=&quot;language-bash &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;$ todx view
☑  Make a great website
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now lets create another todo:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;bash&quot; class=&quot;language-bash &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;$ todx add oops i did it again
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh no. I didn&#x27;t wish to create this todo.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can delete it using:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;bash&quot; class=&quot;language-bash &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;$ todx del
0 ☑  Make a great website
1 ☐  oops i did it again

Which todo you want to delete: 1
Are you sure buddy? [Y&amp;#x2F;n] Y
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You select your todo just like in the &lt;code&gt;todx mark&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; command. And then it confirms wether you really want to delete your todo. (ProTip: If you just press Enter at the confirmation, it assumes yes)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just run &lt;code&gt;todx&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;todx view&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; to check that you have successfully deleted a todo. There is no trash feature yet so the deleted todo &lt;strong&gt;cannot&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; be recovered.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This much is everything you need for a simple basic commandline todo app.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TodX is simple yes, but not basic.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;advanced-commands&quot;&gt;Advanced commands&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You mave have noted the absence of quotes while using the &lt;code&gt;todx add&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; command. You can definetly do &lt;code&gt;todx add &amp;quot;Some todo&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; but it takes time to add those quotes and it doesn&#x27;t feel elegant. Hence todx is designed in a way to eliminate the need for the quotes. You can always use quotes if you want to be more pragmatic.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use &lt;code&gt;-a&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;add&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;-m&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;mark&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;tags&quot;&gt;Tags&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us say you want to organize your todos. Say that you want to sepearate your homework todos from your personal projects. It would be nice to have two different todo lists for both. But maybe you might have two lists of &lt;em&gt;holiday&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;thing to buy&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;, now if you want to add a todo &lt;em&gt;Buy a swimsuit&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; You may want to add it to both of your lists, but this will introduce redundancy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To simplify this problem, todx uses &lt;strong&gt;tags&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. Each tag starts with a &lt;code&gt;+&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; followed by a word, if there are several words use dashes to join them. You can add a tag to a todo while creating it by simply writing &lt;code&gt;+tagname&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; anywhere after the add command. (Although it is recommended to add them at the last since it is how they are displayed)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So lets add a todo with a tag:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;bash&quot; class=&quot;language-bash &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;$ todx add Complete math homework +school
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you view the todos:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;bash&quot; class=&quot;language-bash &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;$ todx
☐  Complete math homework  +school
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us add another todo:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;bash&quot; class=&quot;language-bash &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;$ todx add Make science project +school +projects
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now to view todos of only &lt;code&gt;project&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; tag, use the command:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;bash&quot; class=&quot;language-bash &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;$ todx +project
+ project
☐  Make science project
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow, It only displays undone todos of tag project. What if you want to view all todos? Just run:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;bash&quot; class=&quot;language-bash &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;$ todx view +project
+ project
☐  Make science project
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;sync&quot;&gt;Sync&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the data of todx is stored in a single &lt;code&gt;data.json&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; file (in linux located at &lt;code&gt;~&#x2F;.local&#x2F;share&#x2F;todx&#x2F;data.json&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;). Since this file is a json, it can be easily synced with a remote server and can be used in any other app that might support the json format. Android and Web apps can de made that use this extendability.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;customizability&quot;&gt;Customizability&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently things like done markers that define which status elements are marked as done and unicode charecter replacements (&lt;code&gt;☐&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;☑&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; etc) are stored in &lt;code&gt;settings.py&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; in the main code. I intend to make a &lt;code&gt;settings.json&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; file similar to &lt;code&gt;data.json&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; to add user customizability.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-bash-setup&quot;&gt;The Bash setup&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;code&gt;todx&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; is commandline tool we can easily mix and match it with other commandline tools to create beautiful things. I created a simple script to run everytime I start my terminal telling me the current weather, a smal quote and my todos. Here is a screenshot:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blag&#x2F;images&#x2F;todx-setup-bash.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-i-learnt&quot;&gt;What I learnt&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was and is an exhilarating project. I leant a lot of new stuff and revised old python skills in the process. Firstly I got to finally and successfully save and load data from json files into userdefined python objects.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next I got to know about &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;ActiveState&#x2F;appdirs&quot;&gt;appdirs&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; package which let me use default os directories to save datafiles.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also learnt how to process command line parameters and install the package as a binary rather than just a library.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally I got to learn about the python packaging tools. I learnt how to make a package and how to publish it to pypi. Fun fact : TodX is listed in the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;pypi.org&#x2F;project&#x2F;todx&#x2F;&quot;&gt;pypi&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Making a python package takes some getting used to and can be daunting for many beginners. I almost quit my plan putting the package on pypi in the process. Perhaps I would make a blogpost describing the process.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-future&quot;&gt;The Future?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed this is just the beginning of TodX. I have several plans about todx which I would like to implement as soon as I get time to work on it. Some of them include:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making a server and syncing &lt;code&gt;data.json&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding tests&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding tty colors to make the program more beautiful&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding created time and due date with support for notifications&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hopefully creating a simple android app to sync with (currently TodX runs nicely in &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;termux.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Termux&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Why xypnox?</title>
		<published>2018-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/why-xypnox/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/why-xypnox/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;cover-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;&amp;#x2F;blag&amp;#x2F;images&amp;#x2F;why-xypnox-cover.jpg&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;desc&quot;&gt;
    Why though?
  &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;backstory&quot;&gt;Backstory&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time, I was introduced to email. And my first email was from yahoo.com (Which by now is most probably destroyed). It had the most common naming scheme, namely, your name followed by your birth year.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as time passed, I moved on to Gmail, and I made a new email. It also went along the lines of the well-known name + year scheme. But I was getting tired of the long email and most importantly of my teenage browsing habits that had collectively subscribed to enough services that it was impossible to filter the important emails from promotions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, being the smart person I was, I didn&#x27;t unsubscribe to these services. Rather, I created a new email that I planned to use for serious work! It was &lt;em&gt;adityaultra4 @ gmail.com&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. I chose &lt;em&gt;ultra&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; because obviously, it was cool and &lt;em&gt;4&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; because it was one of my favorite numbers. (At least it&#x27;s better than &lt;em&gt;adityarocking2000&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used the adityaultra4 username in almost all things I signed up for, Github, Twitter etc, etc. But, then I ran into a problem. By some way or another, I used the shorter version &lt;em&gt;adiultra&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; in some services instead of the longer &lt;em&gt;adityaultra&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. This slight mismatch infuriated me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-search&quot;&gt;The Search&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence, one day, out of the blue, I decided that enough was enough and I wanted a new alias. Something short that I could use everywhere. At that time I was a huge fan of Greek mythology, having read the Percy Jackson series. I used google translate to look up for cool greek words. I translated all the hyper-ultra-super-awesome-sounding words into greek and tested whether they were taken or not.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most difficult service to get a username is Gmail. Almost all the Greek words were already taken (Thanks helpful people of Greece), so, I started using variations. Slight changes to words that won&#x27;t deviate much and will be sure to not have a registered account. More importantly, they should be pronounceable, because my favorite webcomic was named by using four random letters (&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;xkcd.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;xkcd&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), and when I recommend it to people they mostly take it for a nerdy geek thing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Greek word that I finally stumbled upon was &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;translate.google.co.in&#x2F;#el&#x2F;en&#x2F;%CE%AD%CE%BE%CF%85%CF%80%CE%BD%CE%BF%CF%82&quot;&gt;έξυπνος&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (&lt;em&gt;éxypnos&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;). It means smart, clever, ingenious etc in English. Perfect! But the e in the beginning wasn&#x27;t too nice. So, I removed the &lt;em&gt;e&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; and It now also meant &lt;em&gt;Awake&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;! Obviously, xypnos was already taken on Gmail. So, I had to improvise again. This time removing the last letter and replacing it with the good old &lt;em&gt;x&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. And &lt;em&gt;xypnox&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; was finalized.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;logo&quot;&gt;Logo&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I needed a logo, an image for my profile pictures. Something that spoke of xypnox when people saw it. And for apparent reasons, I choose the greek &lt;code&gt;chi&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; &lt;strong&gt;χ&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. I could use any color I wanted and it was easy to scale, it looked good at both small and large sizes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blag&#x2F;images&#x2F;xypnox-logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;LOGO&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viola! xypnox was available at all the services that were relevant to me and I quickly set up an account for them as soon as possible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I have pretty much a very consistent username system for me. So, good that if you Google &lt;em&gt;xypnox&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; all the content to show up would be mine.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is the one and only story of me getting the name &lt;em&gt;xypnox&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Design Tips</title>
		<published>2018-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/design-tips/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/design-tips/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;cover-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;design-tips-cover.jpg&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;desc&quot;&gt;
    Cover found on the Internet
  &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, I have been practicing the art of designing web pages for a long time (a few years at least). And I have made some (objective term) progress. Here I would present some resources that you can go through to help in designing websites. Also, I would recommend a few tips which would help you boost your design.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;observation&quot;&gt;Observation&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first good skill that you need to obtain to start designing is Observation. Look and Observe how others have designed their websites. Also, do not limit yourself to a standard site such as Google or Facebook for design inspiration. You can browse these sites for a taste of what good design looks like:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cssdesignawards.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;CSS Design Awards&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; Look here for the best of the best, But Don&#x27;t be overwhelmed and depressed. These are the best-designed websites&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cssmania.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;CSS Mania&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cssdsgn.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;CSSDSGN&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;html5up.net&#x2F;&quot;&gt;HTML5up&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; I would recommend only to observe the design and if needed download and learn how to design a specific thing rather than copy-pasting the whole template. You would complete the website; But would you learn?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another amazing tool to help you in the task of observation is &lt;strong&gt;Developer Tools&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. These are available in all major browsers. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;developers.google.com&#x2F;web&#x2F;tools&#x2F;chrome-devtools&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Chrome DevTools&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;developer.mozilla.org&#x2F;en-US&#x2F;docs&#x2F;Tools&quot;&gt;Firefox Developer Tools&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. A cool tip to note: you can add new styles in DevTools and see them updated live on the webpage, Awesome for testing different colors padding etc to see what fits right. (Note that changing code in DevTools does not change it in your files)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;understanding-color&quot;&gt;Understanding color&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;design-tips&#x2F;Designer-joke-color.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Color&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I agree that color theory is a vast topic and I don&#x27;t quite understand all of it, I still can recommend a few websites from where I have developed my sense of color:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.smashingmagazine.com&#x2F;2010&#x2F;01&#x2F;color-theory-for-designers-part-1-the-meaning-of-color&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Color Theory for Designers - Smashing Magazine &lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
I love the Smashing Magazine Blog. They cover detailed explanations and examples of design. And this blog series, in particular, is a gem. I have developed most of my color choice from these articles. Make sure you read all three!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.smashingmagazine.com&#x2F;2016&#x2F;04&#x2F;web-developer-guide-color&#x2F;&quot;&gt;A Simple Web Developer&#x27;s Color Guide&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
Another article from Smashing Magazine. Nice and simple.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enough about theory what about Tools?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.colorhexa.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ColorHexa&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; - Literally they say themselves as a color encyclopedia&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.palettable.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;PALETTABLE&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; - Create a color palette by liking&#x2F;disliking (It ain&#x27;t FB)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.colourlovers.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;COLOURlovers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; - The site where I found great colors. Also, check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.colourlovers.com&#x2F;palettes&#x2F;most-loved&#x2F;all-time&#x2F;meta&quot;&gt;Top palettes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on this site, they are beautiful.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;color.adobe.com&#x2F;create&#x2F;color-wheel&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Adobe Color CC&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; - Don&#x27;t Worry it&#x27;s free! It&#x27;s also amazing, especially for extracting color from images.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.gpick.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;GPick&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; - I use this tool a lot to collect the colors I love. It&#x27;s available in Ubuntu repos as &lt;code&gt;gpick&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;using-fonts&quot;&gt;Using Fonts&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;design-tips&#x2F;Designer-joke-font.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Font&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most dramatic effect of any one thing on design is that of the font. (Just think of designing something in Comic sans except of course Comics). I really like typefaces. And here are some sites to learn more about them:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;pixel77.com&#x2F;principles-of-typography&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Design Theory: 5 Basic Principles of Typography&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; - Sums up the basic points of using typefaces&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;webdesign.tutsplus.com&#x2F;articles&#x2F;choosing-the-right-font-a-practical-guide-to-typography-on-the-web--webdesign-15&quot;&gt;Webdesign
Choosing the Right Font: A Practical Guide to Typography on the Web&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting the right fonts is not a headache, thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;fonts.google.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Google Fonts&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It&#x27;s an amazing site from where you can download and even link your fonts through CSS&#x2F;link tags so that the font is shown in your client&#x27;s browser even if they haven&#x27;t installed it!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few other sites that provide free fonts but most of them either are free for personal use or cost some $Dolla.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also compiled a set of great fonts available on Google fonts when I created the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;xypnox&#x2F;fontstaller&#x2F;&quot;&gt;FontStaller&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; script. You can find them &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;xypnox&#x2F;fontstaller&#x2F;releases&#x2F;download&#x2F;v1.0.0&#x2F;fonts.zip&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;tips-n-tricks&quot;&gt;Tips n Tricks&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;minimalism-is-the-way-to-go&quot;&gt;Minimalism is the way to go&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minimalism is not a lack of something. It’s simply the perfect amount of something. — Nicholas Burroughs&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By having a lot of things on the website at the same time confuses people and gives a sense of clutter and disorder. Put something there only if it needs to be there. Simplify Reduce Iterate. Just look at Wikipedia. It isn&#x27;t quiet aesthetic as other sites and looks like a mess in the modern age. Whereas a quick look at Google explains the point of simplicity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;design-tips&#x2F;Screenshot-Wikipedia.png&quot; alt=&quot;Wikipedia&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;design-tips&#x2F;Screenshot-Google.png&quot; alt=&quot;Google&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But don&#x27;t remove everything. As once a great man said:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything should be made as simple as possible, but not simpler. - Albert Einstein&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;test-different-screen-sizes&quot;&gt;Test different screen sizes&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xypnox.com&#x2F;blag&#x2F;posts&#x2F;design-tips&#x2F;responsive-design.png&quot; alt=&quot;Responsive&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know it is hard to design for your own screen size, much harder to design for several. But that is what makes or breaks a design. People would not just be browsing your website from your specific machine. They might use a phone a tablet or unfortunately a smart-TV. Make your website at least a little mobile friendly by adding a few media tags.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;advance-stuff-sass&quot;&gt;Advance stuff : Sass&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since I learned about &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;sass-lang.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Sass&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, I have used it everywhere. It is a CSS preprocessor. By that I mean, it is a language that compiles to generate CSS. But why would we need something else? Because it simplifies things. Here is the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;sass-lang.com&#x2F;guide&quot;&gt;official guide&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; if you are feeling curious.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;use-some-extensions&quot;&gt;Use some extensions&lt;&#x2F;h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know editing CSS files is not that hard, you don&#x27;t need extra debugging stuff and linters. But a few extensions do make the job easier. These are a few extensions that I use in &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;atom.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Atom&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;atom.io&#x2F;packages&#x2F;color-picker&quot;&gt;color-picker&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; I love this plugin&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;atom.io&#x2F;packages&#x2F;pigments&quot;&gt;pigments&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; this one too&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;atom.io&#x2F;packages&#x2F;css-snippets&quot;&gt;css-snippets&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;atom.io&#x2F;packages&#x2F;language-css&quot;&gt; language-CSS &lt;&#x2F;a&gt; This comes as preinstalled.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading, Hope I might have been of some assistance in your Aim to nail down the best design ever!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Fontstaller</title>
		<published>2018-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/fontstaller/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/fontstaller/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;cover-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;&amp;#x2F;blag&amp;#x2F;images&amp;#x2F;fontstaller-cover.jpg&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;desc&quot;&gt;
    Install fonts quickly on linux
  &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have had troubles installing fonts in Linux. Although its far easier than Windows where the only way to install a bunch of fonts is to open the file and click install fonts. In Linux however, you can copy your fonts to &lt;code&gt;~&#x2F;.fonts&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;&#x2F;usr&#x2F;share&#x2F;fonts&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; and they will be recognized by all the applications. But can this process be improved or streamlined?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main problem that I was facing was that while many sites offered fonts for free they were usually zipped&#x2F;archived. Which meant that they would have to be manually unarchived one by one to install the fonts, which considering the number of fonts (36!) I wanted to install at the time was way too much. So clearly I needed a script to unzip and copy the font files in &lt;code&gt;~&#x2F;.fonts&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. The problem was that although the &lt;code&gt;unzip&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; command is fairly straightforward and could be used I didn&#x27;t have much control over it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I searched some more and stumbled upon the fact that python comes preloaded with a zip archive reading library named &lt;code&gt;zipfile&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. And I could use it to spin up a small python script to make the extraction process &amp;quot;smart&amp;quot;. By smart, I mean that the program could differentiate between a directory containing fonts and archives containing fonts. It can also work with nested directory structure and even detect whether a font has been preinstalled or not.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-program-itself-fontstaller&quot;&gt;The program itself: FontStaller&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;raw.githubusercontent.com&#x2F;xypnox&#x2F;fontstaller&#x2F;master&#x2F;fontstaller-logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Logo&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the code in the GitHub repo &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;xypnox&#x2F;fontstaller&#x2F;&quot;&gt;xypnox&#x2F;fontstaller&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the default settings, the Fontstaller script installs the fonts located in the folder &lt;code&gt;fonts&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; in the current directory. It installs all the zips that have a font file. Or any (sub - sub ...) subdirectory (ies) that have a font file (generally ttf, otf).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fonts are by default copied to the folder &lt;code&gt;~&#x2F;.fonts&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. An interesting point to note is that the directory structure of your initial &lt;code&gt;fonts&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; folder is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; preserved. This is to simplify distinguishing already installed fonts. This way the script can easily check only folder names in &lt;code&gt;~&#x2F;.fonts&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; and doesn&#x27;t have to deal with subdirectory structure.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few command line options to tweak the behavior of the script, they are mentioned as follows:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;argument&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;th&gt;default&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;th&gt;description&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;&lt;&#x2F;thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;-h, --help&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;show help message and exit&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;--fdir&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&#x27;fonts&#x27;&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;directory containing fonts&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;--idir&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&#x27;~&#x2F;.fonts&#x27;&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;directory in which fonts will be installed&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;--ignorezip&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;Ignore zipped files&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;tbody&gt;&lt;&#x2F;table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know there are few bugs that still exist. Such as the fact that the script doesn&#x27;t deal well with subdirectory structure in the archived files. However, it is still quite useful.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in the fonts I was installing, check this &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;xypnox&#x2F;fontstaller&#x2F;releases&#x2F;download&#x2F;v1.0.0&#x2F;fonts.zip&quot;&gt;archived zip&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;hr &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;tricks&quot;&gt;Tricks&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learned a few new tricks about python scripting that I would share here.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;splitting-and-slicing-simultaneously&quot;&gt;Splitting and slicing simultaneously&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You split and slice simultaneously by just splicing the output of Splitting command. For example, the line in my code that uses it is :&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;python&quot; class=&quot;language-python &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-python&quot; data-lang=&quot;python&quot;&gt;idir = args.idir + &amp;#x27;&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x27; + zfile.split(&amp;#x27;&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x27;)[-1][:-4]
&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here I needed only the name of the archive without the &lt;code&gt;.zip&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; extension. So I first split the string using &lt;code&gt;&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; then slice the last element till the fifth last character. Pretty neat.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;parsing-command-line-parameters-in-python&quot;&gt;Parsing command-line parameters in python&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know its quite dumb to say it&#x27;s a trick but it took me several readings of Manual and a few different command line parsing methods to flat this one out. I finally ended up using the &lt;code&gt;argparse&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; package which is a little hard, to begin with, but offers a great amount of flexibility and nice user experience such as auto-generated &lt;code&gt;help&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; command!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is too much, to begin with, so I will simply link to its Manual page in Python : &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.python.org&#x2F;3.6&#x2F;library&#x2F;argparse.html&quot;&gt;Argparse&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Misfits</title>
		<published>2018-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/misfits/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/misfits/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here is one of the greatest quotes I know of.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Here&#x27;s to the crazy ones. The misfits. The rebels. The troublemakers. The round pegs in the square holes. The ones who see things differently. They&#x27;re not fond of rules. And they have no respect for the status quo. You can quote them, disagree with them, glorify or vilify them. About the only thing you can&#x27;t do is ignore them. Because they change things. They push the human race forward. And while some may see them as the crazy ones, we see genius. &lt;em&gt;Because the people who are crazy enough to think they can change the world, are the ones who do.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&amp;quot;
― Rob Siltanen&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Losing Things</title>
		<published>2018-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/losing-things/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/losing-things/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some very beautiful things get lost and forgotten. Just as I got lost. - Luise Rainer&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;blag&#x2F;images&#x2F;comic-losing-things.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Comic&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all lose things all the time, sometimes they are simple things such as an eraser, but many a times we lose significant things. I created this graph to plot the relation between how hard it is to loose something and how much hurt we feel when the thing is lost!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy! (And probably share if you like it)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>XKCD</title>
		<published>2018-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/xkcd/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/xkcd/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;cover-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;&amp;#x2F;blag&amp;#x2F;images&amp;#x2F;angular_momentum.jpg&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;desc&quot;&gt;
    Angular Momentum
  &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the best XKCDs, there are many more at : &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;xkcd.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;xkcd.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: Its my favorite webcomic!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;angular-size&quot;&gt;Angular Size&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;imgs.xkcd.com&#x2F;comics&#x2F;angular_size_2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;Angular Size&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;ancient-stars&quot;&gt;Ancient Stars&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;imgs.xkcd.com&#x2F;comics&#x2F;ancient_stars_2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ancient Stars&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;altitude&quot;&gt;Altitude&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;imgs.xkcd.com&#x2F;comics&#x2F;altitude_2x.png&quot; alt=&quot;Altitude&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;approximations&quot;&gt;Approximations&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;imgs.xkcd.com&#x2F;comics&#x2F;approximations.png&quot; alt=&quot;Approximations&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;beliefs&quot;&gt;Beliefs&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;imgs.xkcd.com&#x2F;comics&#x2F;beliefs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Beliefs&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;compass-and-straightedge&quot;&gt;Compass and Straightedge&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;imgs.xkcd.com&#x2F;comics&#x2F;compass_and_straightedge.png&quot; alt=&quot;Compass and Straightedge&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;complex-conjugate&quot;&gt;Complex Conjugate&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;imgs.xkcd.com&#x2F;comics&#x2F;complex_conjugate.png&quot; alt=&quot;Complex Conjugate&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;convincing&quot;&gt;Convincing&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;imgs.xkcd.com&#x2F;comics&#x2F;convincing.png&quot; alt=&quot;Convincing&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;creepy-relatableaf&quot;&gt;Creepy #RelatableAF&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;imgs.xkcd.com&#x2F;comics&#x2F;creepy.png&quot; alt=&quot;Creepy&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>A Beautiful Morning</title>
		<published>2018-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/a-beautiful-morning/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/a-beautiful-morning/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today was a beautiful morning&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
The sun was shining&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
through a cloak of clouds.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
The flowers, bright and fragrant,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
were vibrant in the glow of sunlight.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The breeze was cool and calm,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Just enough to ruffle your hair.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in the midst of the heavenly morning,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
I was sad, and desolated.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because all the beauty of the world couldn&#x27;t match yours,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
And all the grief of the world couldn&#x27;t match mine.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conceived during cycling to lectures, Not everything I write relates to me&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Quotes</title>
		<published>2018-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-02-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/quotes/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/quotes/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are a collection of Quotes, some mine, some salvaged from others.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I don&#x27;t mind your thinking slowly; I mind your speaking faster than you think.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; - Wolfgang Pauli&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sometimes, we have to take the paths we hate the most to get to places we most like.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; - @xypnox&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With great power comes great trouble. Responsibility comes later.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; - @xypnox&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Development is one percent inspiration and 99 percent documentation.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; - @xypnox&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The difference between good and bad is the difference between what you should do and what you do.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; - @xypnox&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;World War III will be fought not by soldiers but by hackers.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; - @xypnox&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Every human is like a coin. He has two sides a good one and a bad one. I however am a dice.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; - @xypnox&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You&#x27;ve spent too much time looking at one face of the coin that you have denied the existence of the other.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; - @xypnox&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you can do anything good then don&#x27;t do it for free&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; - Joker.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Anything that can happen will happen&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; - Interstellar.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The universe prefers the improbable to prevent the impossible.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; Found on Wikipedia.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A beautiful thing is never perfect.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our greatest glory is not in never failing but rising everytime we fall.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Be careful not to choke on your Aspirations&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sometimes it&#x27;s the very people who no one imagines anything of who do the things no one can imagine.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; - Imitation Game&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hardest time to lie to somebody is when they&#x27;re expecting to be lied to.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; - Imitation Game&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;I don&#x27;t want to survive. I want to live.&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; 12 Years a Slave&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Mama says, &#x27;Stupid is as stupid does.&#x27;&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; Forrest Gump&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;The greatest trick the devil ever pulled was convincing the world he didn&#x27;t exist.&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; The Usual Suspects&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;Frankly, my dear, I don&#x27;t give a damn.&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; Gone With the Wind&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Love cannot be found where it doesn’t exist, nor can it be hidden where it truly does.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; – David Schwimmer, from Kissing a Fool&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oh yes, the past can hurt. But you can either run from it, or learn from it.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; – Rafiki, from The Lion King&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why are you trying so hard to fit in when you were born to stand out?&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; – from What a Girl Wants&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Life moves pretty fast. If you don’t stop and look around once in a while, you could miss it.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; – Ferris, from Ferris Bueller’s Day Off&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We are who we choose to be.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; – Green Goblin, from Spider-Man&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don’t let anyone ever make you feel like you don’t deserve what you want.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; – Heath Ledger, from 10 Things I Hate About You&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I don’t regret the things I’ve done, but those I did not do.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; – from Empire Records&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is not our abilities that show what we truly are… it is our choices.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; – Dumbledore, from Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Don’t ever let somebody tell you you can’t do something, not even me. Alright? You dream, you gotta protect it. People can’t do something themselves, they wanna tell you you can’t do it. If you want something, go get it. Period.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; – Chris Gardner, from The Pursuit of Happyness&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Life is not the amount of breaths you take it’s the moments that take your breath away.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
-Will Smith (Hitch)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;One day a researcher is doing an experiment with frogs. He cuts one of the frog&#x27;s legs off. He ordered the frog to jump, and it did. Then he cut off one of the frog&#x27;s arms off. He then ordered the frog to jump again, and it did as it was told. He continued to do this until he had cut all of the frog&#x27;s appendages off. He then ordered the frog to jump, and the frog couldn&#x27;t. The rescearcher then wrote in his notes: when I cut all of a frog&#x27;s legs off it becomes deaf.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;quot;You cannot be certain about uncertainty.&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; — Frank Knight&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The word &amp;quot;reality&amp;quot; is also a word, a word which we must learn to use correctly.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; - Bohr&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An expert is a man who has made all the mistakes which can be made in a very narrow field.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; - Bohr&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The worthwhile problems are the ones you can really solve or help solve, the ones you can really contribute something to. … No problem is too small or too trivial if we can really do something about it.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; - Feynman&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Politicians use statistics in the same way that a drunk uses lamp-posts; for support rather than illumination.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; - Andrew Lang&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The best parts of you are hidden where you’re most afraid to look&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Most of the people who really ain’t got it try to go out of their way to show people that they have it&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By the time a man realizes that maybe his father was right, he usually has a son who thinks he’s wrong.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; - Charles Wadsworth&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I must say to myself that I ruined myself, and that nobody great or small can be ruined except by his own hand.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; - Oscar Wilde, De Profundis&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;One often meets his destiny on the road he takes to avoid it&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Lonely</title>
		<published>2018-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/lonely/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/lonely/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;cover-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;&amp;#x2F;blag&amp;#x2F;images&amp;#x2F;lonely.jpg&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;desc&quot;&gt;
    Photo by Brannon Naito on Unsplash
  &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see you down the street, alone&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Walking slowly towards me&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
In the cold hazy wind&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
That twirls your hair lightly&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your eyes stare the drab pavement&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Your light steps make no sound&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
You slightly move your hand to remove&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
The falling hair from your pale face&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
And my heart skips a beat&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a moment you lift your eyes&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
And we gaze at each other&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
I smile, but you have already looked away&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
A few seconds pass, while I&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Dream of you&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I look at you again and I see,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
The sad pain of loneliness, your eyes&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Have lost the shine they once had&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Your bag full of books is&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Dragging you down&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe we can meet someday,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
And extinguish our loneliness together&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
For I recognize the suffering, the ache&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
Of being lonely&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Happy New Year</title>
		<published>2017-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2017-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/happy-new-year/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/happy-new-year/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;cover-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;&amp;#x2F;blag&amp;#x2F;images&amp;#x2F;new-year.png&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;desc&quot;&gt;
    A Happy New Year Post, Quote from Brainyquotes | Photo by Karl Magnuson on Unsplash, edited by me :)
  &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thats pretty much it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want the full res image you can get it from &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;imgur.com&#x2F;a&#x2F;EM7Qs&quot;&gt;imgur&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share the image if you like it, Also add the link to this post.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i.e. &lt;code&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;git.io&#x2F;vbbwB&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>My experience with Linux</title>
		<published>2017-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2017-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/my-experience-with-linux/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://www.xypnox.com/blag/posts/my-experience-with-linux/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;cover-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;&amp;#x2F;blag&amp;#x2F;images&amp;#x2F;penguins-cover.jpg&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;desc&quot;&gt;
    Penguins! The ever present symbol of Linux | Photo by Yuriy Rzhemovskiy on Unsplash
  &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to share My Linux experience here and how I finally ended with Ubuntu Mate.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am an Indian college fresher now (20 Dec 2017).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got my first computer when I was in 3rd Standard (aged 7 or 8). It was a HCL PC preloaded with Windows XP. But somehow the seller had removed the orignal activated one, and installed another pirated version of XP with several softwares. I used the computer for several years just to play games online and do stupid stuff. I was completely ignorant of anything like Linux and Free software. India still faces this problem, very few know about the free open source softwares.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PC had a Intel Pentium processor, 2 GB of RAM, and a 1600x900 resolution display, 300GB Hard Disk. No Discrete Graphics.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this changed when I moved to Agra, the city of Taj. There in my seventh or eighth standard, A guy boasted about how his OS was linked to the PC’s motherboard and how if it went corrupt it could burn the entire motherboard. I was intrigued by it, I knew nothing about operating systems other than Windows. That was my age when I had newly realised that I could search the web and learn from it (I had self-learned a very little html from the internet). I inquired and he named the OS as Ubuntu (He pronounced it You-buntu).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I searched about this OS and It came out as just another operating system, the catch being it was free. I remember the release of Ubuntu I downloaded, it was Saucy Salamander (13.10). The name itself was quite interesting it itself. And then on a 3GB&#x2F;month internet I downloaded the release (About 800+ MB).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then I installed it from a Disc, It was Great. It was fast, new, and more efficient than Windows 7 that I ran on the PC. I used it for a lot of time, but since it could not run MS office, or any games that I loved I simply removed it by deleting the partition and then unfortunately screwing up with grub, I had to reinstall Windows 7.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then used my PC normally for a year or two, but later the PC performed poorly on windows, It ran slow, terribly slow. So I reinstalled Ubuntu and then I discovered the free software community, And wow was it amazing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then got to know that there were several alternatives to popular Windows only apps. I also came to like the free software foundations Principals. I till then still didn’t know of various other Linux Distros.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a day just browsing the web, I came to a page of best Linux distros, I read it and then searched on google about “Distros”. I then understood that I had a choice to install different distros and different Desktop Environments. I searched a lot and Elementary OS attracted my attention. It was new then and it was very pleasing to look at. It also was quite user-friendly, (My family wasn’t much enthusiastic of me installing a different OS (according to them) every once in a while).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I installed the Elementary OS and it was great. It lacked many Unity features but it still worked for me. I was delighted by it. I learned Python and C++ on elementary OS. This was also the time when I first contributed to an Open Source project, I designed the Icon for Mark My Words (an elementary app). I then contributed a little here and there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I later tried installing the newer Release of Freya 0.3.1. It didn’t install for some reason and I had to look for other options. I looked for Ubuntu again, but this time I looked at its other flavors.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first booted Ubuntu Gnome and I disliked it straight away, it was the gnome shell. I then turned to Kubuntu, it had the new and flashy+modern KDE 5. And boy it looked awesome. It didn’t run Gnome apps that good (they looked horrible). And KDE5 was still quite buggy and unstable, I think they might have fixed it now. I used Kubuntu for two to three months before looking for other options.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then by miracle I discovered Ubuntu Mate. I read an article in OMG Ubuntu about the UMate becoming an official flavour. I researched (a synonym for Googled) about Umate and I found it quite pleasing, just the right apps in a minimal distro. I installed it and I was hooked.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then never worried about anything. I installed 16.04 later and removed Windows for good, since it was a LTS release. I was actually quite fed up reinstalling different OSes and I wanted stability from then on. I worked later on Ubuntu Mate for everything, mostly programming. (I even customized their community website and added a few wallpapers to some releases).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used the username @adiultra back then, now I have switched to @xypnox&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then this year December 2017, I bought an XPS 15 for college. It was worth a fortune but I am quite happy with it. Also the first thing I did was dual-boot Umate 16.04.3 on it. I have not completely removed windows on this because I sometimes get MSOffice files which don’t go so nicely with Libre Office. And yes I wanted a little gaming once in a while.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still am not perfectly happy with UMate and I think a few things can be improved here and there, But its far better than Windows. In fact UMate launches Atom in less than 2 seconds while Windows takes a good load of 12 seconds (on a hyper powerful laptop).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this was my tale with Linux. Hope you liked it!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
