<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on The Blag</title>
    <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on The Blag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 22:10:55 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://xypnox.github.io/blag/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/quotes/</guid>
      <description>These are a collection of Quotes, some mine, some salvaged from others.
 I don&amp;rsquo;t mind your thinking slowly; I mind your speaking faster than you think. - Wolfgang Pauli
Sometimes, we have to take the paths we hate the most to get to places we most like. - @xypnox
With great power comes great trouble. Responsibility comes later. - @xypnox
Development is one percent inspiration and 99 percent documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a Physics undergraduate student at IIT Kharagpur. I have interest in Programming, Open Source, Physics and Gadgets. My other name is Aditya Vikram Singh. Know about the story of getting the name here.
 Science is art and art is science, there are no exceptions.
 You can find my website/portfolio at xypnox.com
You can reach me here:
 Github Twitter Telegram &amp;lt;== text me here Instagram Facebook  You can also email me at xypnox @ gmail .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why xypnox?</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/why-xypnox/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 22:10:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/why-xypnox/</guid>
      <description>Backstory Once upon a time, I was introduced to email. And my first email was from yahoo.com (Which by now is most probably destroyed). It had the most common naming scheme, namely, your name followed by your birth year.
But as time passed, I moved on to Gmail, and I made a new email. It also went along the lines of the well-known name + year scheme. But I was getting tired of the long email and most importantly of my teenage browsing habits that had collectively subscribed to enough services that it was impossible to filter the important emails from promotions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>