<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>design on The Blag</title>
    <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/tags/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in design on The Blag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 19:26:01 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://xypnox.github.io/blag/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Typography</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/typography/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 19:26:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/typography/</guid>
      <description>Typography is the art and technique of arranging type. It is the method used to make text readable, legible, beautiful and meaningful. Good typography is readable. No matter how stylish and polished your font is, if it isn&#39;t readable no one is gonna read it.
 The beauty of type lies in its utility; prettiness without readability serves neither the author not reader. - James Felici
 The main way in which we style our texts is with fonts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing a Poster</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/designing-a-poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 23:05:44 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/designing-a-poster/</guid>
      <description>To design a good poster, you have to design 100 bad posters first.
 I have been making posters for a couple of years. And I have learned a lot, not just about how to make a good poster, but also why most posters are bad. And here I present a minimal guide on how to make nice posters.
I should say upfront that I am not a great designer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Tips</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/design-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 22:49:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/design-tips/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I have been practicing the art of designing web pages for a long time (a few years at least). And I have made some (objective term) progress. Here I would present some resources that you can go through to help in designing websites. Also, I would recommend a few tips which would help you boost your design.
Observation The first good skill that you need to obtain to start designing is Observation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>