<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Blag</title>
    <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Blag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 19:48:28 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://xypnox.github.io/blag/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/quotes/</guid>
      <description>These are a collection of Quotes, some mine, some salvaged from others.
 I don&#39;t mind your thinking slowly; I mind your speaking faster than you think. - Wolfgang Pauli
Sometimes, we have to take the paths we hate the most to get to places we most like. - @xypnox
With great power comes great trouble. Responsibility comes later. - @xypnox
Development is one percent inspiration and 99 percent documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a Physics undergraduate student at IIT Kharagpur. I have interest in Programming, Open Source, Physics and Gadgets. My other name is Aditya Vikram Singh.
FAQs Why xypnox? Why Blag? How is this blag made? This blag is made through a static site generator called hugo. The theme I am currently using is called blag-theme.
 You can find my website/portfolio at xypnox.com
You can reach me here:
 Github Twitter Telegram &amp;lt;== text me here Instagram Facebook  You can also email me at xypnox @ gmail .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing a problem in Chess</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/chessproblems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 19:48:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/chessproblems/</guid>
      <description>So I was interested in this chess puzzle:
In this very peculiar position we have to place the black king to a square such that it is not in check and with white being next to move black gets mated in the maximum number of moves. That is white takes most moves to mate black.
To solve such a problem, we can take help of our friend Stockfish. Using the online chess website Lichess&#39;s analysis and editor features, we can determine the number of moves to mate for all the available squares.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nettigritty Fraud</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/nettigritty-fraud/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 18:23:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/nettigritty-fraud/</guid>
      <description>Just so everyone knows
 Date: Fri, 8 Nov 2019 18:19:02 +0530
Subject: I am deeply unsatisfied with your business policy
To: support@nettigritty.com
Cc: mail@hackinout.co
 Hi Nettigritty,
Your company is an awesome company, it has great services and exceptional policies, including the one to give free domains to the Hackathon participants, so that they may utilize it. And if what they make is successful, they will gladly pay the registration fees after the first year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing a Poster</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/designing-a-poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 23:05:44 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/designing-a-poster/</guid>
      <description>To design a good poster, you have to design 100 bad posters first.
 I have been making posters for a couple of years. And I have learned a lot, not just about how to make a good poster, but also why most posters are bad. And here I present a minimal guide on how to make nice posters.
I should say upfront that I am not a great designer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps that I Love</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/apps-that-i-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 15:43:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/apps-that-i-love/</guid>
      <description>Along the several years, I have been using computers and smartphones, I have discovered a few real gems that have adorned my gadgets. I present here a list of Applications, for desktop and mobile that I have loved using and would recommend to anyone within a heartbeat.
Maybe you may already know some of them but perhaps the reasons why I like them would differ from yours, so read on!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One of the Dark Days</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/one-of-the-dark-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 19:47:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/one-of-the-dark-days/</guid>
      <description>I fall too soon and too deep
Into waters I am unaware of.
And I forget to swim
When I need to.
I inhale the water
Knowing all well,
that it isn&#39;t well.
And then I cry,
Try to find faults
In others when I am wrong,
And in myself when others have wronged.
I find myself
At crossroads
Where every road is a bad omen.
And yet, I have to choose one</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two Pens</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/two-pens/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 23:19:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/two-pens/</guid>
      <description>In a busy school,
two friends sat together
in mutual distrust.
Each buying the same
luxury pen last weekend
and that hurt
their swag level.
The first of the two
used the pen far and few
the second didn&#39;t.
He abused the pen
to scratches and scuffs
having no care at all,
for him, it was
just another pen.
Days passed, Weeks passed.
The first&#39;s pen shinned,
where the seconds dulled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving Notes to Github</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/moving-notes-to-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 22:39:53 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/moving-notes-to-github/</guid>
      <description>I never had a unified place to store notes earlier. I usually just remembered important things and wrote down the other things anywhere I liked. But after a year in college I could not keep on remembering everything. I should make it clear early on that I do not take extensive notes. I only jot down things that I find important like thoughts, quotes, project ideas, some literature etc. I had always looked for a simple note taking solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Elderling Realm</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/the-elderling-realm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 20:41:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/the-elderling-realm/</guid>
      <description>The elderling realm is not a single book. It is not even a series of books, it is a universe in which several series written by the author Robin Hobb take place. I completed three series out of five main series released till now. And I have thoroughly enjoyed her work. The books are very easy to recommend and are considered classics among recent fantasy novels. I will try to keep this review as free from spoilers as I can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TodX : The Todo Manager</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/todx-the-todo-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 00:31:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/todx-the-todo-manager/</guid>
      <description>So, I have been working this past few weeks on a todo application using commandline interface in Python. You can skip the boring backstory and jump right into installation if you want to.
 The project&#39;s source code is available at GitHub
 Backstory I recently switched to i3 windows manager just to try it out. And I loved it. I have now become used to living in the terminal. Most of the work except web browsing can be done through the terminal in an efficient way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why xypnox?</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/why-xypnox/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 22:10:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/why-xypnox/</guid>
      <description>Backstory Once upon a time, I was introduced to email. And my first email was from yahoo.com (Which by now is most probably destroyed). It had the most common naming scheme, namely, your name followed by your birth year.
But as time passed, I moved on to Gmail, and I made a new email. It also went along the lines of the well-known name + year scheme. But I was getting tired of the long email and most importantly of my teenage browsing habits that had collectively subscribed to enough services that it was impossible to filter the important emails from promotions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Tips</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/design-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 22:49:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/design-tips/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I have been practicing the art of designing web pages for a long time (a few years at least). And I have made some (objective term) progress. Here I would present some resources that you can go through to help in designing websites. Also, I would recommend a few tips which would help you boost your design.
Observation The first good skill that you need to obtain to start designing is Observation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fontstaller</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/fontstaller/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 12:02:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/fontstaller/</guid>
      <description>I have had troubles installing fonts in Linux. Although its far easier than Windows where the only way to install a bunch of fonts is to open the file and click install fonts. In Linux however, you can copy your fonts to ~/.fonts or /usr/share/fonts and they will be recognized by all the applications. But can this process be improved or streamlined?
The main problem that I was facing was that while many sites offered fonts for free they were usually zipped/archived.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misfits</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/misfits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:01:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/misfits/</guid>
      <description>Here is one of the greatest quotes I know of.
&amp;ldquo;Here&#39;s to the crazy ones. The misfits. The rebels. The troublemakers. The round pegs in the square holes. The ones who see things differently. They&#39;re not fond of rules. And they have no respect for the status quo. You can quote them, disagree with them, glorify or vilify them. About the only thing you can&#39;t do is ignore them. Because they change things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Losing Things</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/losing-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 20:50:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/losing-things/</guid>
      <description>Some very beautiful things get lost and forgotten. Just as I got lost. - Luise Rainer
 We all lose things all the time, sometimes they are simple things such as an eraser, but many a times we lose significant things. I created this graph to plot the relation between how hard it is to loose something and how much hurt we feel when the thing is lost!
Enjoy! (And probably share if you like it)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XKCD</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/xkcd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 15:30:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/xkcd/</guid>
      <description>Some of the best XKCDs, there are many more at : xkcd.com
PS: Its my favorite webcomic!
Angular Size Ancient Stars Altitude Approximations Beliefs Compass and Straightedge Complex Conjugate Convincing Creepy #RelatableAF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Beautiful Morning</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/a-beautiful-morning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 19:36:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/a-beautiful-morning/</guid>
      <description>Today was a beautiful morning
The sun was shining
through a cloak of clouds.
The flowers, bright and fragrant,
were vibrant in the glow of sunlight.
The breeze was cool and calm,
Just enough to ruffle your hair.
But in the midst of the heavenly morning,
I was sad, and desolated.
Because all the beauty of the world couldn&#39;t match yours,
And all the grief of the world couldn&#39;t match mine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lonely</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/lonely/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 00:05:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/lonely/</guid>
      <description>I see you down the street, alone
Walking slowly towards me
In the cold hazy wind
That twirls your hair lightly
Your eyes stare the drab pavement
Your light steps make no sound
You slightly move your hand to remove
The falling hair from your pale face
And my heart skips a beat
For a moment you lift your eyes
And we gaze at each other
I smile, but you have already looked away</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Year</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/happy-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 13:35:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/happy-new-year/</guid>
      <description>Happy New Year
Thats pretty much it.
If you want the full res image you can get it from imgur
Share the image if you like it, Also add the link to this post.
i.e. https://git.io/vbbwB</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My experience with Linux</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/my-experience-with-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 22:59:52 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/my-experience-with-linux/</guid>
      <description>I would like to share My Linux experience here and how I finally ended with Ubuntu Mate.
I am an Indian college fresher now (20 Dec 2017).
I got my first computer when I was in 3rd Standard (aged 7 or 8). It was a HCL PC preloaded with Windows XP. But somehow the seller had removed the orignal activated one, and installed another pirated version of XP with several softwares.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>