<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Blag</title>
    <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Blag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 22:49:01 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://xypnox.github.io/blag/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Quotes</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/quotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/quotes/</guid>
      <description>These are a collection of Quotes, some mine, some salvaged from others.
 I don&amp;rsquo;t mind your thinking slowly; I mind your speaking faster than you think. - Wolfgang Pauli
Sometimes, we have to take the paths we hate the most to get to places we most like. - @xypnox
With great power comes great trouble. Responsibility comes later. - @xypnox
Development is one percent inspiration and 99 percent documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/about/</guid>
      <description>I am Aditya Vikram Singh aka xypnox.
I am a Physics Student at IIT Kharagpur.
You can find my website/portfolio at xypnox.github.io
You can reach me at various social sites.
 Github Facebook Twitter Telegram &amp;lt;== text me here Instagram  You can also email me at xypnox @ gmail . com (Be smart and remove those spaces ;))</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Tips</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/design-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 22:49:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/design-tips/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I have been practicing the art of designing web pages for a long time (a few years at least). And I have made some (objective term) progress. Here I would present some resources that you can go through to help in designing websites. Also, I would recommend a few tips which would help you boost your design.
Observation The first good skill that you need to obtain to start designing is Observation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fontstaller</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/fontstaller/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 12:02:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/fontstaller/</guid>
      <description>I have had troubles installing fonts in Linux. Although its far easier than Windows where the only way to install a bunch of fonts is to open the file and click install fonts. In Linux however, you can copy your fonts to ~/.fonts or /usr/share/fonts and they will be recognized by all the applications. But can this process be improved or streamlined?
The main problem that I was facing was that while many sites offered fonts for free they were usually zipped/archived.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misfits</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/misfits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:01:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/misfits/</guid>
      <description>Here is one of the greatest quotes I know of.
&amp;ldquo;Here&amp;rsquo;s to the crazy ones. The misfits. The rebels. The troublemakers. The round pegs in the square holes. The ones who see things differently. They&amp;rsquo;re not fond of rules. And they have no respect for the status quo. You can quote them, disagree with them, glorify or vilify them. About the only thing you can&amp;rsquo;t do is ignore them. Because they change things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Losing Things</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/losing-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 20:50:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/losing-things/</guid>
      <description>Some very beautiful things get lost and forgotten. Just as I got lost. - Luise Rainer
 We all lose things all the time, sometimes they are simple things such as an eraser, but many a times we lose significant things. I created this graph to plot the relation between how hard it is to loose something and how much hurt we feel when the thing is lost!
Enjoy! (And probably share if you like it)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XKCD</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/xkcd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 15:30:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/xkcd/</guid>
      <description> Some of the best XKCDs, there are many more at : xkcd.com
PS: Its my favorite webcomic!
Angular Size Ancient Stars Altitude Approximations Beliefs Compass and Straightedge Complex Conjugate Convincing Creepy #RelatableAF </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Beautiful Morning</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/a-beautiful-morning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 19:36:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/a-beautiful-morning/</guid>
      <description>Today was a beautiful morning
The sun was shining
through a cloak of clouds.
The flowers, bright and fragrant,
were vibrant in the glow of sunlight.
The breeze was cool and calm,
Just enough to ruffle your hair.
But in the midst of the heavenly morning,
I was sad, and desolated.
Because all the beauty of the world couldn&amp;rsquo;t match yours,
And all the grief of the world couldn&amp;rsquo;t match mine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lonely</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/lonely/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 00:05:29 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/lonely/</guid>
      <description>I see you down the street, alone
Walking slowly towards me
In the cold hazy wind
That twirls your hair lightly
Your eyes stare the drab pavement
Your light steps make no sound
You slightly move your hand to remove
The falling hair from your pale face
And my heart skips a beat
For a moment you lift your eyes
And we gaze at each other
I smile, but you have already looked away</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Year</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/happy-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2017 13:35:04 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/happy-new-year/</guid>
      <description>Happy New Year
Thats pretty much it.
If you want the full res image you can get it from imgur
Share the image if you like it, Also add the link to this post.
i.e. https://git.io/vbbwB</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My experience with Linux</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/my-experience-with-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 22:59:52 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/my-experience-with-linux/</guid>
      <description>I would like to share My Linux experience here and how I finally ended with Ubuntu Mate.
I am an Indian college fresher now (20 Dec 2017).
I got my first computer when I was in 3rd Standard (aged 7 or 8). It was a HCL PC preloaded with Windows XP. But somehow the seller had removed the orignal activated one, and installed another pirated version of XP with several softwares.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>