<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on The Blag</title>
    <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on The Blag</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 15:43:25 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://xypnox.github.io/blag/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps that I Love</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/apps-that-i-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 15:43:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/apps-that-i-love/</guid>
      <description>Along the several years, I have been using computers and smartphones, I have discovered a few real gems that have adorned my gadgets. I present here a list of Applications, for desktop and mobile that I have loved using and would recommend to anyone within a heartbeat.
Maybe you may already know some of them but perhaps the reasons why I like them would differ from yours, so read on!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fontstaller</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/fontstaller/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 12:02:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/fontstaller/</guid>
      <description>I have had troubles installing fonts in Linux. Although its far easier than Windows where the only way to install a bunch of fonts is to open the file and click install fonts. In Linux however, you can copy your fonts to ~/.fonts or /usr/share/fonts and they will be recognized by all the applications. But can this process be improved or streamlined?
The main problem that I was facing was that while many sites offered fonts for free they were usually zipped/archived.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My experience with Linux</title>
      <link>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/my-experience-with-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 22:59:52 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xypnox.github.io/blag/posts/my-experience-with-linux/</guid>
      <description>I would like to share My Linux experience here and how I finally ended with Ubuntu Mate.
I am an Indian college fresher now (20 Dec 2017).
I got my first computer when I was in 3rd Standard (aged 7 or 8). It was a HCL PC preloaded with Windows XP. But somehow the seller had removed the orignal activated one, and installed another pirated version of XP with several softwares.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>